Chapter 6: My Past Is Not Today

Gellert Grindelwald's handsome face was grinning, despite being locked in three-way duel with his former best friend, Albus Dumbledore, and his brother Aberforth.

"Give it up, Albus. This is our birthright, and if you are too weak to claim it, then I have no further use for you. But I don't wish to hurt you!"

Albus slashed the air violently with his hand, only barely fending off the writhing tendrils of roots that had burst from the ground at Gellert's command. "Only if you swear to me to stop this madness. You've seen the price! Forty-five million dead? Even you can't pretend that's for the greater good!"

"Do you really think that we, the chosen of Atlantis, should be held culpable for blood on the hands of a mayfly leader of a Muggle country?" Gellert laughed as he effortlessly deflected the wall of ice that Albus had sent his way. "Besides, if you care so much about saving those Muggles, just send an owl to the Viennese Academy for Fine Arts in a few years"

A bolt of red light shot forth from Aberforth's wand. Unlike his brother, Aberforth was aiming to kill, not to subdue.

Another effortless deflection, another laughing taunt.

"I like your brother's style, Albus. I bet if it were up to him, he'd just kill the boy. Just take a quick jaunt down to Michaelsbergstraße, Aberforth... Burn the whole street down, just to be sure. If you love Muggles so much, I'm not sure why you don't!"

"Avada Kedavra!"

A gust of wind from Albus' hand blasted Gellert out of the way of the curse, and knocked Aberforth off his feet, his wand clattering a few feet away.

"Aberforth! Are you insane?"

The younger Dumbledore glared up at his older brother in rage, then looked past him to the object of his hatred. "He's rotting your brain, Albus. If you don't have the stomach to do it, then I will. It's 'for the greater good', after all," he spat, mockingly, while diving for his wand.

Grindelwald laughed, regaining his stance and twisted his wand in a telltale corkscrew pattern.

"NO!" Albus shouted, slashing his wand desperately. Gellert winced, withdrawing his hand which began blossoming blood. The curse had also struck a glancing blow across the side of Grindelwald's scalp, who wiped the blood out of his eyes with his free hand.

Aberforth had reached his wand by this point, and right before he fired a curse at Gellert, he saw Albus drawing a shield with his free hand, so he changed his plan: he flicked his wand to the side, casting a concentrated sonic lance which pierced the air and broke Albus' concentration.

The shield shattered, and Aberforth leapt up, slicing his wand low to destabilize Gellert's footing, preventing him from effectively dodging, then flicked a wide blade upward which could not be avoided by falling or jumping. As soon as Gellert felt the ground beneath him shift, he predicted Aberforth's vertical attack, and he cast a cord of rippling purple light outward. The rope wrapped itself around one of the support beams of the outdoor porch, and Gellert yanked hard, swinging himself out of the way of the blade and toward Aberforth.

As Grindelwald prepared to attack from overhead, an awkward angle from which to defend against, he felt the weight of Albus Dumbledore crash against him and carry them both to the ground. He stared up into Albus' eyes, which were but a few inches from his face, feeling Albus' hot breath against his lips.

Gellert spat insolently at Albus, "Lesz egy ember akit a villám megjelölt és ő kioltja majd a csillagokat."

As Albus was about to respond, he was interrupted by the sound of the door from the house opening, timidly. A small, young girl wearing a gray dress, with a mop of messy, blonde hair peered out from behind the door. She turned her walleyed gaze towards Albus, and lit up with excitement.

Aberforth gaped with horror. "Ari, you... you're not supposed to be here."

Albus looked back down at Gellert, who spoke to him with intensity, "Albus, you speak of forty-five million Muggles? That's but a fraction of the hundred billion that have lived and died since Atlantis. Sacrifices must be made, for the-"

Albus' hand, which was now running through Gellert's hair, gripped it firmly and yanked it backwards. "Don't say it, don't you dare say it. You never believed it, that's the difference between you and me. It was always a mask to you."

In silent response, Gellert pulled Albus face close, and kissed him, passionately. A few yards away, Ariana tittered and bounced up and down on her heels, ogling them and giggling excitedly.

"Does that look like a mask, to you?" Gellert whispered. Albus was dazed. He had dreamed of this moment for quite some time, and he found he had quite some difficulty come to his senses. "Come with me, Albus. We can rebuild this broken world... together." He whispered this last word, breathlessly, into Albus' ear.

Aberforth had moved protectively between the two of them and Ariana, and sighed loudly. "Really? Now? He's toying with you, Albus." He kept his wand trained on the two of them and his free hand on Ariana's shoulder, trying to slowly guide her back into the house.

Hot tears formed at the corners of Albus' closed eyes, and he whispered a single world that echoed with finality.

"No."

Aberfoth's tense posture noticeably slackened. Ariana cocked her head, quizzically. Grindelwald sighed.

"You stupid, stupid boy." Violently, he shoved Albus off of him, rolled aside, and jumped up. "I'm leaving, Albus. Without you."

Without further dramatics, he began to walk away, approaching the edge of the wards around the house that would have prevented him from Disapparating. When he finally reached the faintly shimmering veil, he turned around and spoke.

"But of course..." he nodded his head towards Aberforth,"I can't let him live to stop me."

And with that, a violent crackle reverberated through the air as forked lightning shot towards Albus and Aberforth. In instantaneous response, both Aberforth and Albus shot forth spells of their own. Aberforth knew that Albus would react defensively for both of them, and shot a bolt of pure elemental force in Gellert's direction which would have been instantly fatal had it connected. Albus knew that Aberforth would not bother with defense, and despite the inevitable war that would come, he could not bear to see Gellert die. Not here, not now.

Three points of brilliant intensity shot forth, intercepting Gellert's lightning and Aberforth's elemental blast. The six streams of magic danced in the early twilight, casting shadows of deep violet, ivory, and aquamarine. The magic reverberated in sinusoidal waves, casting off sparks and fireworks both beautiful and terrible. The three grunted in magical exertion, desperately trying to maintain the force of their own magic. Pure offense was easily outmatched by pure defense in a one-on-one duel; but Albus' power was divided between both Gellert and Aberforth, and for a moment, it seemed like none of them would prevail.

Until...

"Ooo... shiny..."

Ariana, enamored by the dazzling light show, wandered from behind Aberforth, and held her hand outstretched towards the display of crackling magic. Aberforth, Albus, and Gellert's eyes went wide in horror. As her hand reached closer and closer, it was Aberforth who broke first.

"Ari, stop!"

Like removing one of three legs of a stool, the balance had been shattered. The magical force erupted, and the sky went white. A hot wave of force washed over the four of them with flecks of intertwined magic concentrating in a single direction. If the pulsating bursts of magic hadn't already blasted them backwards, the rumbling of the ground would have knocked them off their feet, where the intensity of the evaporating magic made any sight beyond a few feet all but impossible.

When the air had finally cleared, Gellert was gone, and Ariana was dead. All that Albus Dumbledore could hear before he drifted into unconsciousness was his brother whispering with desperate abandon, "Please... not her... take me instead. Please..."

Alice Longbottom's head was buried in Frank's shoulder, she couldn't bear to look. Frank had a wary eye on Albus Dumbledore, fixedly keeping his gaze away from the box that the house elf had dropped off minutes before. Minerva McGonagall tried to place her hand on Albus' back, but he slapped it away. He paced back and forth, manic.

"What's in the box, Alastor?"

Alastor Moody was the only person in the room who was still staring at the box, the Eye of Vance whizzing erratically back and forth. He did not speak.

In his absence, the ghostly, echoing voice of Lord Voldemort emanated from the open box.

He just told you...

"No. Alastor. Say it's not true."

Alastor shook his head. "I'm sorry, Albus. There's a lot that I'd do for you, but lie to your face isn't one of them."

Become vengeance, Albus...

"What's in the bloody box?!" He shouted, shaking his head in desperation. He didn't need to look. He could feel that he was now alone in sustaining the transfiguration that he had assisted in maintaining at Aberforth's request, nay, demand.

Aberforth was nearly late, and nodded curtly at Albus when he arrived. Albus noted the strange new necklace hanging around Aberforth's neck, a delicate glass collection of five or six interconnected bubbles, but said nothing of it. In fact, they barely said a word to each other until after the funeral, when Aberforth had approached him and taken his hand and placed it upon the necklace.

"Albus, you need to do your part."

Albus cocked his head at this, but then his eyes widened in recognition as he recognized the magic of transfiguration. "Forbearance?" He whispered, glancing back at the closed coffin which had already been lowered into the freshly dug earth of Godric's Hollow.

Aberforth said nothing, but only nodded.

"Surely... surely you don't believe in that rubbish. That's for purebloods, daft fools who worship the Sacred Twenty-"

POW

Albus was gamely interrupted by a fist to the face, which knocked him square off his feet.

"You always were a selfish bastard, Albus. You never liked her, Ariana the Albatross, around the great Albus Dumbledore's neck. She loved you, she adored you... and you, you couldn't even give a damn." Aberforth breathed heavily from the effort of the punch, his voice raising in volume. "It's your fault she's dead. It may not have been by your hand, but it was you that brought it on her."

Albus, still on the ground, was looking stolidly downward, wiping the blood from his broken nose. Aberforth leaned down and roughly lifted him up. "Look me in the eye, Albus. Look at me!" Aberforth demanded.

Still shuddering in anger from both the insult and the physical blow, Albus looked at his brother in the eyes. "I'm sorry, Aberforth."

"If you're sorry, then do this for me. It always burned me that she adored you more than me. When I cared for her more in a day than you had in your entire life. You might not believe in it. Hell, I don't even know if I do, either. Maybe it's just a twisted lie, but it's a comforting one, Albus. You lost your chance to do it for her, but the least you could do is to do it for me."

Aberforth thrust the necklace out in Albus' direction, who nodded and wrapped his hand around it. He felt the magic, the underlying form beneath the substance, and it was unmistakeable. Lifeless, but unmistakeable. Tears coming to his eyes, he let his own magic flow through, reinforcing Aberforth's, maintaining the transfiguration for as long as he would live.

He was jostled out of his recollection by the sound of the door to the swinging open. Amelia Bones and her brother, Edgar strode into the headquarters of the Order of the Phoenix, a hidden set of rooms concealed behind a bookcase in the Headmaster of Hogwarts' office. Oblivious to the mood in the room, she began speaking immediately as the door closed behind her. "Dearborn's gone missing, hasn't made any of the standard check-ins in the last forty-eight hours. We're hoping against hope that he-"

She slowly trailed off as she saw the somber face of Moody, staring into an open box, and Dumbledore pacing back and forth with a crazed expression. Amelia was sharp, she knew that Aberforth had been kidnapped and was held for ransom, and she could put two and two together easily enough.

"Oh, no... No, Albus, no..."

As if Moody was waiting for someone who would be amenable to his suggestion to enter the room, he began speaking, slowly, testing the reaction to his words. "We need to respond. We need to send them a message."

This seemed to be the only thing that Dumbledore reacted to. He nodded, slowly. "Yes... A message."

Minerva, on the other hand, eyed Moody suspiciously. "A message? What kind of... 'message' do you have in mind?" Her lips and voice were both quite thin.

"I'll let Albus answer that one." Moody demurred, looking up at him.

"I... I need a moment. Please, will you all please give me my privacy?"

Without further prompting, the assembled members of the Order of the Phoenix filed swiftly into an adjoining room. When the door had closed behind the last of them, Albus Dumbledore walked over slowly and peered down into the box.

Aberforth's severed head, eyes and mouth open in a silent, bloodcurdling scream of pain, stared up at him. The glass bubble necklace that Aberforth had always worn around his neck was missing, but not gone, as its transfiguration was now maintained by Albus alone, and he could still feel the vague, persistent tug of Magic deep within his person. His brother's head was perfectly preserved; it almost gave off the impression that the box was part of some invisibility cloak that only revealed the head of its wearer.

As Dumbledore suspected, the head was preserved by Voldemort himself, and was impervious to any sort of modification. A perpetual insult, meant to serve as a reminder of the heinous deed, but ultimately turned into a weapon against its maker. When Voldemort had supposedly been defeated that fateful Halloween night a year later, the first thing Dumbledore had done after hearing the news was retreat into the private room in his office, discovering that the head was still intact, perfectly preserved.

He knew, at that moment, that the Dark Lord had not truly died, but had merely fallen. Voldemort's hold over the transfiguration, though still present, had weakened, and Dumbledore had used that opportunity to alter the form of Aberforth into something less painful to look upon: an ornate ring set with a brilliant sapphire, engraved with a stylized set of goat horns, and he wore that ring on his finger from that day forth.

In the present, though, Dumbledore had noticed glistening, silvery tears in Aberforth's eyes, swimming with telltale white wisps: clearly a memory preserved, and Albus didn't need to guess which of Aberforth's memories that Voldemort had left him with. Nonetheless, Albus collected them in a small silver phial, approached his Pensieve, and steeled himself for what was to come.

Later

"Narcissa, take Draco and go! It's him!" shouted a man's voice. "Go! Run! I'll hold him-"

His voice was cut off by a wordless, almost lazy flick of a wand, and the intruder advanced.

"Not Draco, not Draco, please not Draco!" screamed the woman's voice.

"Step aside, woman," said the cold, dispassionate voice. "I have not come for you, only the boy."

"Not Draco! Please... have mercy... have mercy..."

She flung her arms protectively in front of the door at the back corner of their bedroom, as if a wandless witch with little to no battle experience could somehow turn aside the indomitable wrath of Albus Dumbledore.

"I give you this rare chance to flee," said the cold voice. "But I will not trouble myself to subdue you and your death here will not save your child. Step aside, foolish woman, if you have any sense at all!"

"Not Draco, please no, take me, kill me instead!"

Albus Dumbledore cocked his head as if deeply considering this. After an endless moment, he finally spoke. "Very well," said the voice of death, sounding coldly resigned. "I accept the bargain. Yourself to die, and the child to live. Now step forward so that I can murder you."

There was a hideous silence.

Albus Dumbledore began to chant, a horrible, rhythmic chant.

Az-reth, Az-reth, Il-dan, Il-dan, Ma-ev, Ma-ev

As twisted fire began pouring out of the flaming rune that Dumbledore had conjured, a percussive crack filled the room as Lucius Malfoy managed to break through his immobilization, and he shrieked in desperate hate, "Avada ke-"

A gust of air slammed him against the back wall, knocking the wind of out him, preventing him from completing the incantation. Dumbledore held him firmly in place with magic emanating from his outstretched hand, and casually guided the crackling flame above the bed.

Lucius struggled mightily, screaming, yet producing no sound, as Dumbledore flicked his wand, sending Narcissa screaming onto the bed.

"Incarcerous!"

Thick, black cords emerged from the aether, binding her firmly to the four posts of the Malloy's lavishly appointed bed. Amid the crackling of flames and Narcissa's shrieks, the faint sound of a small baby boy crying wafted from the adjacent room.

Satisfied that Narcissa was properly bound, Dumbledore whirled on his feet and turned to Lucius, holding his wand underneath Malfoy's chin. "You were there, weren't you?" he asked, quietly.

Lucius did not answer.

"ANSWER ME!"

"Please... not her... take me instead. Please..."

Dumbledore's mouth turned up in a twisted smile. "My brother spoke those same words as he cradled our sister in his arms." As he spoke, he slowly dragged the Elder Wand up Lucius' chin, across his face, to his forehead, deliberately pushing into his skin hard enough to occasionally draw blood. "But would you know, there was no one to listen? LEGILIMENS!"

The memories of Aberforth's torture and eventual murder slammed into Lucius' mind, as Albus Dumbledore continued to speak. "Your 'Dark Lord' forced him to relive that memory as he tortured him... but you already know this, don't you, Lucius? You were there. You watched as Tom Riddle murdered my brother."

The memories withdrew, and Albus violently flung his hand backwards and cast the rippling cloud of flame that was hovering threateningly over the bed downward, engulfing Narcissa, who immediately let out a bloodcurdling, horrifying scream. Lucius thrashed violently against the invisible bonds that held him, his eyes wide and welling with tears.

"Do you know why Tom Riddle fears me, boy? Do you?"

Lucius could not answer. He stared wide-eyed as he watched the love of his life, the mother of his child, consumed by violent, blood-red flame. Her screams had ceased. A dim part of Lucius' mind wondered if this was because she was dead, or because the part of her lungs capable of screaming had simply burned away.

Dumbledore's voice lowered to a menacing whisper, "He knows what I am capable of, but he does not know where I draw the line."

He moved the wand deliberately down Lucius' face, down his side, to the top of his leg. The wand's tip glowed the same shade of red as the burning flames, and he pressed it to Lucius' skin, who began writhing with physical pain to match the emotional. He slowly drew a line down Lucius' leg, leaving a trail of sticky, liquid flame which charred and bubbled the flesh beneath.

"You tell Tom Riddle, if you survive, that he has crossed that line, and if he crosses that line again..."

Albus Dumbledore held his hands up, and a blazing Phoenix crashed through the window. When its claws caught his hands, he exploded in a fanstastic burst of flame, which scattered across the room.

The curse which rendered Lucius immobile evaporated, dropping him to the ground. He tried to stand up, but his leg would not support his weight from the pain of the liquid flame. As he dragged himself across the bedroom floor to the door that opened into Draco's room, he heard the booming voice of Albus Dumbledore complete the sentence:

The world will burn!

"Albus Percival Wulfric Brian Dumbledore, what have you done?!" Minerva McGonnagal demanded, half-shrieking, half-hissing, staring down at the unconscious, but unharmed body of Narcissa Malfoy.

Dumbledore's head was firmly planted in his hands, and he did not look up at her.

"We agreed that you'd take the boy! As abominable as I find the idea of using an innocent baby as a piece of meat, at least we all agreed upon a plan! But this, this is a grown woman, Albus! "

Without warning, Alastor Moody had clambered into the chamber and began speaking without introduction or preamble.

"I agree with Minerva. We can't just stuff her in a cradle and change her nappies and expect her to keep quiet until we're ready to trade her back to the Malfoys! And besides, ol' Lucius is a lot more likely to get sentimental about his son than his wife, I expect." His magical eye whizzed around in his head a few times before fixing itself upon Narcissa's supine body. "Although..."

James Potter scoffed, idly playing with a Golden Snitch. "Always the delicate one, Alastor."

Dumbledore looked up at Lily and James through his fingers. "And what say you, James?"

James shrugged. "We had to send a message, didn't we? Judging by the state of you, I'd say you did just that."

Albus nodded. "And it almost destroyed me... anyone who can bring themselves to play the role of a monster-"

"-Yes, yes, they're a monster too. Take a good look at me, Albus. Yer' not a monster. I can guarantee you that whatever it is you did tonight wouldn't hold a candle to some of the things I've done on a mild day." He leaned in closer. "And I wasn't acting."

"We've all heard your lecture on how rotten you are, how you can cast the Killing Curse at will, at how much you wanted Grice dead, blah blah blah..." James cut in with a smile, and then contorted his voice into a thick brogue in open mockery of Moody. "I didn't do it for justice, or to stop him, I did it because I wanted him dead."

Lily giggled. "I, for one, am glad to have heard his lectures. It's good to know my limits. You know me, I'm always giving people the benefit of the doubt." James rolled his eyes at her, and she decided to toy with him a bit. "You know, I bet I wouldn't even be able to manage a Killing Curse if Voldemort himself turned up in our house."

James groaned and Lily laughed. "Lily, don't make a liar out of me, I'm always telling people how good you are with a wand!" She mussed his already-mussed hair as he protested.

"You should watch out for how much you talk me up. I don't know how much good I'd be able to do in this state. I'm about to burst." She gestured down to her distended stomach, and James warmly laid his head down upon it.

"At least you're here today, which is more than I can say for Alice. She's due any day now, too, isn't she?" Suddenly, his eyes lit up. "He kicked! He kicked, did you feel it?" James' wand, which was sticking out of his back pocket, glowed a faint golden.

Lily rolled her eyes, "If you can feel it through mystomach..."

Moody made a fake retching sound, "Alright, you two, you can wait until you get back to Godric's Hollow for that namby-pamby nonsense. We need to come up with a plan."

Dumbledore finally looked up from his hands. "As it so happens, Alastor, I do have a plan." As if on cue, a loud knock came from outside the Headmaster's office, and Dumbledore and Minerva quickly left the chamber and closed the bookcase behind them, leaving James and Lily alone with Alastor Moody. They listened intently to the voices from inside the Headmaster's office.

"Coming!" They heard Dumbledore shout pleasantly.

The opening of a door. A bombastic, loud voice, "Greetings, Greetings, Headmaster! A pleasure to see you, sir. What can I do for you, or you for me?"

"Thank you for answering my call at such a late hour, Gilderoy. I'm afraid I have a favor to ask of you..."

Lucius gazed at the mantle in the Oblatorium of Malfoy Manor, staring at the figurines. Each one a different, unique sculpture, each representing a departed family member. As he stroked them, he could feel the magic that maintained the transfiguration flow through not only him, but all those who knew and loved the departed. That is, until he reached her figurine; a small, gilded lyre bathed in mint green light.

It was deliberate, burning her away to ash, not allowing her to take part in the Ritual of the Forbears. Denied an honor that was extended to even the lowest of House Elves, after a fashion.

The Lyre represented the Lyre of Orpheus, who had travelled into the Underworld in order to save the one he loved. Narcissa was always fond of that story, and it was their little joke that one of them would have to be the other's Orpheus. But that was no longer possible. She was gone. She no longer existed. She was absolutely annihilated and was not coming back.

With each generation, the magic that maintained the transfigurations grew weaker. He and his brethren would do anything to stop that from happening. Not for their own sake, but for the sake who all who came before them. They would ally with any tyrant, make any sacrifice, pay any price... And that price had come due. Guilty of no crime but loving Lucius, his Narcissa, his beautiful, innocent Narcissa, had been denied the Awakening.

He noticed that his cane was rattling on the floor as he leaned on it for support. The pain of his cursed leg was still raw. Duller now, but it would take years for it to fully subside. He stroked the silver serpent at the top of the cane and lost himself in watching his infant son playing on the floor, unaware of the turmoil that lay beneath his father's steely visage.

Chapter 7: Dr Swann's Proposal

June 7, 1992
Hogwarts

"No, Amelia," Dumbledore spoke, wearily. "I do not think it is something to worry about."

Dumbledore had been steadfastly ignoring the urgent calls from Azkaban, alerting them that one of their Dementors had gone missing.

"That's the second one in a matter of months, Albus."

"I'm well aware. Although, I cannot pretend to be saddened by the loss of one of these monstrous creatures."

"And I'm well aware, Albus," Amelia Bones mocked in frustration, "of your disdain for doing what needs to be done when it fails to line up with your well-signaled virtues. At this rate, Azkaban will be unguarded within a few years."

"Yes, and what a pity that would be," Dumbledore replied, dryly.

"Be as high-minded as you want, but unless you can build us another Nurmengard, we need them."

"I would consider it my life's greatest achievement if I could do so."

"But you can't!" Amelia shouted, her voice distorting through the two-way mirror. "And that's my point! You may have bested Grindelwald in battle, but in this matter, you were not his equal."

Dumbledore sighed. "Yes, I know that, and it pains me every day."

"This has something to do with the Potter boy," Amelia changed tacks abruptly.

"Oh?" Albus asked pleasantly. "But, then again, doesn't everything?"

Bones grunted, half in agreement, half in frustration. "We need to work together on this. We fight the same enemy, Albus."

"It is true, that you and I fight the same enemy. But as for the boy, I fear he does not think as small-minded as we two fools."

"Tell me if you learn anything new from him," she dismissed his cryptic response.

"Oh Amelia," he replied politely. "When have I ever been forthcoming about my secrets?"

"That will get us into trouble one day, Albus. Bones out." And at that, the mirror went dark.

When Dumbledore was sure the mirror was no longer transmitting, Dumbledore pulled out the sopping wet, black tattered cloak that he had retrieved from the Black Lake not minutes earlier, having been alerted to its presence and subsequent destruction by the death wards surrounding Hogwarts.

He smiled, despite himself.

Earlier
The Hogwarts common.

The next morning after meeting with Dumbledore, Harry noticed an unusually large crowd gathered outside on the commons. It was mostly boys, although there were a handful of girls; few that he recognized, though. Ashley Bahl was one of them, the only remaining descendent of Phegor Bahl, inventor of the famed Bahl's Stupefaction. He also recognized Nymphadora Tonks, although she was looking a bit more... roguish than usual. He looked up to see what the crowd was staring at, and up in the sky, on a broom, he saw Rainbow Witch dashing through the air on a broomstick, doing tricks and plainly loving the attention. She seemed very natural, as if the sky was where she was meant to be.

When she spotted him, she shouted down to him. "Hey, Harry! Yeah, you! Come on up here, I heard you're really good on one of these!"

Out of nowhere, Oliver Wood thrust a broom into his hands, and several of the boys around him whistled appreciatively and gave him large, exaggerated winks. Although, for the life of him, he couldn't understand why. "Go on, Harry!" Wood urged.

Tentatively, although swiftly, he rose in the air to meet her.

"You're not too bad, that was a speedy ascent!" She called to him.

"Yeah, I'm not exactly proud of it."

"Why not?"

"I happen to believe that taking unnecessary pride in physical prowess is..." He tried to think of a term that she would properly respond to," ...lame."

"You're the lame one!" She spat.

"Good one?"

She was idly riding in circles around him, turning upside down on occasion. "Come on, isn't this fun? What's the point, otherwise?"

Harry rolled his eyes. "I could think of a lot of things that would be a lot better use of my time than flying around on tool primarily used for cleaning floors."

"Oh yeah? Like what?"

"Oh, I don't know, trying to bring my friend back? Trying to bring your friend back?"

Rainbow Witch paused, briefly. "Oh. Yeah, I guess that's important. But do you think your friend would really want you just wasting your life, moping around? Or do you think she'd want you having fun?"

Harry was ready to deliver a biting reply, but he thought for a moment. This was the sort of question Pinkie Pie would have asked him. But, if he really thought about it, and if he asked Hermione honestly, she wouldn't want him just moping around. "Probably not. You know, your friend, Pinkie Pie, we had a pretty similar conversation about this."

"Yeah, that doesn't surprise me. Pinkie likes fun even more than I do, and that's saying something."

Harry bobbed up and down on the broom for a moment, thinking how to phrase his question. "So, do you all... you know, respect her? She mentioned that, well, how do I put this? She made a lot of scarily accurate guesses about me, things that you'd really only be able to figure out if you were insanely observant, logical, and very good at making accurate predictions. But you all don't really seem to treat her like she's very smart."

Rainbow Witch laughed a bit at this. "Oh, one of her hunches, huh?"

Harry nodded emphatically. "Yes, that's exactly what she called it. But when I asked her about it, she said that no one really asks her to explain herself."

"Well sure, I learned to stop asking her ages ago. The last time she tried to explain one of her hunches to me, she wound up talking about grambitational pull and terminal philosophy and reference fangs for about thirty minutes and she totally lost me."

Harry could only barely piece together what he assumed Pinkie Pie was talking about. "So you all have physics, where you come from?"

"Well, duh! Of course we have physics. What else do you think keeps the world running?"

Harry grumbled in frustration. "I mean, do they teach physics?" Harry only just noticed that Rainbow Witch was staring at him in expectation, and realized too late that he had fallen for her joke, hook, line, and sinker.

She laughed uproariously at him and spun around him a few times. "Yes, they teach physics. Jeez, you need to lighten up, or you're not going to have many friends."

Harry rolled his eyes again. "Are you going to give me friendship lessons now, too?"

"Probably? Me and my friends, we're called all over the place to solve friendship problems." She could see that he wasn't following, so she continued. "Where I'm from, we have a big map of the world that lets us know when there's a friendship problem that needs to be solved. We call it the 'Friendship Map', but Discord told us that we should call it the 'Ball of Prophecies' while we're here."

Harry couldn't help but grin at the ridiculousness of Discord's arbitrary names. "And it told you to come here?"

"Yeah. Well, kind of. Twilight, she's been visiting this world on and off for years, now. But for a while, she's been really freaking out about this one prophecy, one that we already figured out in our world."

Harry's felt an increasingly uncomfortable sense of apprehension. "By any chance does it go something like, 'On the longest day of the thousandth year, the stars will aid in her escape, and she will bring about nighttime eternal.'?"

Rainbow Witch's eyes went wide. "Yeah! Wow, how did you guess?"

Harry shrugged and grinned. "Just a hunch."

She nodded and went on. "Huh! Alright, well, she's been-"

"Wait, wait. You're not even going to ask? You really take these impossibly wild guesses in stride, don't you?"

"Why bother? I mean, you can tell me, but if you start to go all Pinkie on me, I'm going to start doing pinwheels until you're done."

Harry sighed. "Fine, continue."

She had already sped off a few meters and had to brake, hard, when she heard him. She floated back and went on. "Well, anyway. She's been reading into this prophecy, saying something about the "crux", how magic from our world was seeping into yours and was going to cause something terrible to happen unless she was able to "throw the pebble in the pond". Normally, when she visits, she looks like we do now, but this time-"

"Huh?"

Rainbow Witch suddenly seemed to realize that she may have misspoken, and she quickly backtracked. "Doesn't matter. Anyway, she came over to this world, and it was a really long time before we saw her again. Just when we started to get concerned, that's when the Map- er... the 'Ball of Prophecies' lit up and told us to come here."

"So, how long have you all known each other, then?"

"Oh, a pretty long time. Years, at least "

"Since you were kids, then? "

'Ehh, not all of them. I mean, I knew Fluttershy, er... 'Jane', I guess. I knew her growing up. But I met the rest of my friends later. "

"Wait, so how old are you?

"Hm." She seemed to be putting serious thought into the question. "You know, I don't really know."

Harry had heard it was rude to ask a woman her age, so he wasn't sure if this was something that he should pry on. But on the other hand, she didn't seem to be particularly upset or reticent to discuss the subject. "Why not?"

"Well, you just sort of lose track, don't you? I mean, do you know how old you are?"

"Yes, eleven."

"What do you mean, you're eleven? Eleven what?"

"Eleven years...?"

"Right, I don't get it. Eleven years of what?"

Harry was starting to get annoyed. "I mean that in the time between when I was born and today, at least eleven years have passed. How else would I mean it?"

"Are you being serious? You… you're just a baby. Not even a baby."

Harry huffed, defensively. ''How old are you then? Just take a shot in the dark. A wild guess. Older or younger than, say, 20?"

She laughed. "Good one." Harry didn't respond. He didn't even really know how to respond to that. When it was clear that Harry was not going to provide further feedback, she continued. "Well, I know I have to be less than 1000 because I wasn't around for Princess Luna's banishment," she said, mostly to herself.

Harry eyed her. "How long do you think a year is?"

"Um, it's four seasons long, duh."

"Okay... and how long is a season?"

"What do you mean?"

"I feel like the question was pretty self-explanatory."

Getting equally annoyed, herself, she turned the line of questioning around on him. "Okay, how long is a day? "

"24 hours."

"And how long is an hour? "

Harry rolled his eyes. "Okay, I see where you're going here. An hour is 3,600 seconds. And one second is roughly 9,000,000,000 cycles of a cesium atomic clock. But not that it matters. I'm guessing we don't have the same standard units of time, even though we use some of the same words."

"I guess so. One thing I can say is your days are a lot longer than ours. Like, a whole lot longer. It feels like forever since I got to take a nap." She let out an exaggerated yawn.

Harry was diving down a tangential rabbit hole, but this was kind of fascinating. After all, how often does one ever really get to have this kind of conversation?

"OK well, how about this. You mentioned two princesses. How old was the queen when she had them?"

"Queen? We don't have a queen where I'm from. "

"What? Then where did the princesses come from?"

"Yeah, 'Princess' is a title you earn, not one you're born with. What stupid sort of system would let you be a ruler just because of who your parents were?"

Harry laughed, humorlessly. "There are a lot of people, myself included, who would agree with you… But sadly, a lot who would disagree, too. It's a rather progressive idea. "

"It's not 'progressive', it just makes sense."

"Exactly. Progressive. You should see the kinds of things that people believe, here. Racism… Sexism… A lot of people here even think it's bad if you're a boy who likes other boys or…" He tested his next words, gently. "Or a girl who likes other girls… "

She stopped flying, abruptly, and hung in midair glaring at him. "Okay, what is it with this place? You are like, the fifth person to go out of their way to talk about that, about 'boys liking boys' and 'girls liking girls'." She paused for a moment. "Although now that I think about it, you're the first boy that said something… But anyway. Is that... not a thing here?"

"Well… Yes, it's a thing, but… People don't exactly… well, it makes you different. And people don't always like 'different' here."

"Hm." She looked at him thoughtfully. "I guess people must not like you, then. "

"I… Well… Like I said, people don't always like 'different'."

She folded her arms in a self-satisfied manner. "Yeah, I've only been here a few days, and it's obvious you like that blond boy, what's his name, Dracula? And you're a boy… "

"What? Draco? Yes I, look – "

"Come to think of it, I see a lot of girls liking girls and boys liking boys, here... oh… I get it! Is that what this school is for? People who are 'different'?"

Harry stammered out his response, "No, I mean, yes, but. No. Yes, we're different, but, not different like, that… Not that there's anything wrong with that, of course. And me and Draco, we are friends, that's all. I don't think I'm even old enough to really like someone like that. I mean, when did it… Well… OK, forgive me for being so forward but, do you, you know… Like girls?"

She laughed at him. "Well duh. Of course I like girls. Who wouldn't I like somebody just because they're a girl? That's dumb. I like boys, too, for that matter."

Harry couldn't tell if she being deliberately obtuse to get a rise out of him, or if she was blissfully oblivious. "No, I mean… LIKE, like."

Internally, he shook his head at himself. He could not believe that he actually used the phrase 'LIKE, like' in a non-ironic manner. He continued, "As in, do you like girls enough to maybe, one day, eventually, I don't know, have a baby with them? Or," Harry winced. "Do the things that lead to babies being made."

"You mean, travel up to the stars with the Princess of the Night, pick one out, and take it down from the sky?"

"Is THAT how you think babies are made?"

"Well, yeah. That's how Twilight's brother did it. He and Princess Cadence tell me the story all the time."

"They tell you the-" Harry blinked a few times. "Well, it's certainly a creative take on 'the stork'… I hate to break it to you, not that I have personal experience, but the actual process is a lot more… Messy. "

She rolled her eyes at him. "I know that, dummy, I'm a lot older than you are, you know. I just didn't want to go all Sci-Twi and talk about star fusion and quantum identity patterns and Birthing Matrixes and all that boring stuff about how babies are REALLY made."

It was Harry's turn to stop flying in midair and stare, open-mouthed, at her.

"We… It's done a bit differently here. A bit more, uh, organically. So, where you are from, are people even able to have babies without the help of a 'princess', which I assume is some kind of euphemism for 'scientist'?"

"Nice word. And, no, how else would you travel up to the stars?"

Harry stared at her blankly. "So… 'Princess' isn't a euphemism then. "

"Are you sure you know what that word means?"

Harry thought for a moment, vaguely annoyed that his advanced vocabulary was being corrected by a punk rock version of a dumb jock. "Why don't you walk me through exactly what happens when you all… Make babies."

She grinned at him. "Are you sure you can handle it? Well, went two ponies really love each other –"

"Ponies?" Harry cut in.

She blinked a few times and backtracked "It's, uh... It's a euphemism. You know, like the 'birds and the bees'?"

Harry was satisfied, if not confused by the explanation. His brain had been so overloaded with bizarre information that he had temporarily turned off his "pay attention to small notes of confusion" functionality and had shifted into somewhere into 'skeptical credulity' mode. "Sure. So when two 'ponies' really love each other..."

"Yeah, so, when two people want to bring new life into the world, they submit their request to the Princess of the Sun."

Harry had to try very hard to not interrupt her with more questions, which manifested itself as him squirming and fidgeting awkwardly with the hem of his robe. She had paused in anticipation of this but noted his courteous silence. She smiled, and nodded in acknowledgment of his restraint, and continued.

"Whenever a new land is discovered, or," she said the next phrase somewhat hastily, "Whenever there's a vacancy, she will approve the request and send them notification of her choice. Then, on the next full moon, the Princess of the Night will take them into the stars."

Harry was chewing on his fist to prevent himself from shouting out questions.

"They find a star that speaks to them. Well, not, literally, it doesn't talk to them, but, one that, you know, seems to be the right fit. And then the Princess takes it out of the sky, and then..." She paused for a moment, eyeing Harry suspiciously. "Okay, you kind of got me, there. I don't actually know all the science that happens next. All I know is, the star disappears from the sky, and then three seasons later, a baby crawls out of a birthing chamber."

Harry waited a few interminable seconds to make sure that she was completely done, and then he opened his mouth and vomited out a torrent of questions. "What on Earth is the Princess of the Sun? What do you mean 'when a new land is discovered'? What is a vacancy? Are your people sterile, otherwise? Where, physically, are you all located? I'm getting this dystopian future, Neuromancer-type feel to things here."

She tried to take them one at a time. "The Princess of the Sun, she's in charge of… Well, a lot of stuff. One of those things is deciding who gets to bring new life into the world, and when."

"Got it. So the 'sun' the part is a metaphor?"

"Yeah, for the most part. It's definitely not a euphemism."

"You're a jerk."

She cackled and zoomed on her broom a few times around, him leaving iridescent whorls of dust in her wake. "We have people called 'explorers' whose job it is to find new lands and make them suitable for people to live in. But, I think that word is a euphemism because they never seem to actually be exploring. They're always cooped up in the castle at Canterlot, doing science things."

"Do these people, these 'explorers', happen to use telescopes a lot?"

She stopped her circles. "Hey, your hunches are almost as good as Pinkie's!"

"Speaking of Pinkie and hunches, what's your name? I mean, your real name, not the one that Discord gave you. To be honest, I've been calling you Rainbow Witch in my head since I saw you." When she didn't say anything in response, he blurted out, "You know, because of your hair. "

"Well, you're half right. Rainbow Dash is the name, being awesome is my game!"

She flew by him and gave him a hearty pat on the back. He awkwardly tried to return the gesture but missed by a solid half meter.

"Nice to meet you. "

Harry's barometer for prediction felt like a compass that had been shoved up against a massive electromagnet. His current theory, which he assigned credence of 10%, maybe 15% tops, was that Rainbow Dash and her friends came from an advanced human society that had somehow figured out interstellar travel. They clearly hadn't mastered terraforming; otherwise, why would they be living in a tightly regimented, pseudo-post-scarcity dystopia/utopia?

It was only eight or nine months ago that his entire understanding of the world and the universe was turned upside down, so what was one more reality-bending revelation. Although he wasn't totally confident about the whole "portal-generating space humanoids" hypothesis, he assigned much higher credence to his next prediction: The destruction of Atlantis didn't have to be a disaster, what if it was an exodus? Of all the explanations for Magic, the remnant technology of some lost, advanced civilization that had abandoned the Earth for... something... was one of the more plausible ones.

"So, I have another hunch I want to test out. Where you're from, is it called Atlantis?"

Rainbow Dash stroked her chin thoughtfully. "Yeah, I guess."

Rainbow Dash and her friends come from Atlantis: 92%.
Rainbow Dash and her friends are from outer space: 22%.
Rainbow Dash is just messing with me: 6%.

Rainbow Dash continued, "I mean, that's an old name. Like a really, really old name. But that's what they used to call where I'm from."

"What do they call it now?"

"Equestria."

"Ah, I get the pony euphemism now."

"Huh?"

"You all are 'Equestrians'... people who ride... oh, never mind. Ok, so I think I've worked most of it out. But you said something about vacancies. Is that, er... I'm assuming that means when somebody dies."

"Yeah, sure. But I mean how often does THAT happen?"

"Every day?"

"That's not funny."

"What?"

She slowed down, as she could see that Harry was quite plainly not kidding around. In fact, he looked confused. "How often do people…" She worked her mouth around the question "... How often do people die here?"

"Here? Not often. Well, too often," Harry shrugged, bitterly. "But if we're talking about the whole world, and not just here in this castle, then all the time. Probably two or three every second. "

She hung stock still in mid-air, mouth agape. "Two or three every… Second? "

"Sadly, yes."

She didn't move from her position in the air. "How… How do you even live like that? I mean, in the entire time I've been around, I've only heard of one person who... Wait. You don't really mean die, die. You just mean, well what do you mean?"

"Yes, die, die. As in, everything they are and everything they were, gone."

"If this is some kind of prank, you're pretty sick."

"Why on Earth would I joke about this?"

"I don't know. I really hope you are, but you don't sound like you're kidding. "

Something about the genuinely horrified, shocked, stupefied look on her face hit Harry on a visceral level. It was the kind of reaction that someone couldn't fake, or pretend. The absolute horror, the revulsion at the thought of people dying with such sickening frequency. It was written all over her face end it made Harry feel a very deep, very real connection with her.

She was scrutinizing him the same way. Reading his face, seeing if he was kidding, just making a tasteless joke. When she realized he wasn't, that he was dead serious, and masking a seething rage at the very thought of it, she was hit with another wave of emotion. Not the sickening anger of before, but pity, deep overwhelming pity for this boy, this baby in front of her who was subject to, and would likely continue to be subjected to the most unimaginable horror.

Without really thinking about it, she sped her broom towards him and locked her arms around him in a tight hug and patted his back. "I'm sorry."

The cheers and whoops from the students gathered far below were a dim afterthought in Harry's mind. As he returned a hug. "What is it with you people and your tear-inducing hugs?"

"Yeah, that happens a lot. You get used to it." She gave him an irreverent punch on the arm.

Given that Harry didn't have much experience with heartfelt physical displays of emotion, he wasn't quite sure how he was supposed to end things. So he let his arms dangle limply to his sides and gave her an awkward half-wave, half-salute. She cocked her head and laughed at him.

"You're, uh, not very good at this whole 'hug' thing, are you?"

Harry mumbled something unintelligible, then regained his composure. "So you live in this post-scarcity world, huh? And death is... a distant memory, but still there."

Rainbow Dash nodded.

"I have a little... experiment, that I'd like to do. I'm not sure why, but I feel like this is something important."

"Uh, okay."

"But you have to trust me, okay? It might be scary, but you're going to be safe."

"You sound like Applejack. And, 'scary'?" She scoffed at him. "I eat 'scary' for breakfast."

"Good. Now, follow me, we need to go somewhere that people won't be able to see what we're doing."

Meanwhile
Down on the ground

"It's indecent. Inappropriate. And more importantly, it's not fair!" Roger Davies fumed in the general direction of Oliver Wood and Nymphadora Tonks, the few remaining people in the now-dispersed crowd, neither of whom paid him much mind. "He's a firstie! He's eleven! Does he even... you know?"

Tonks rolled her eyes heavily, and Oliver Wood was steadfastly pretending to be thoroughly engrossed in the trimming of his broom's tail twigs. A few other Slytherin quidditch players were watching the unlikely pair up in the sky, trying to track down where they were headed.

"Oi! Wood!" Davies slapped the front of Wood's broom.

"What is it, Davies?"

"I said, does... he... even..." He arched his eyebrows deliberately.

"That's creepy."

Roger clapped his hands together. "Right? Right? See, Nymphadora? Wood agrees. It's creepy."

"That's not even worthy of a 'Don't call me Nymphadora'." Tonks hurled a studded wristband at Davies' head to punctuate her point, forcing him to contort his body to deflect the projectile. "You're the creepy one. You already scared off Ashley Bahl. And you're about to scare me off too."

Wood nodded. "She's right. Just come off it, man. You're embarrassing yourself."

"You're the embarrassing one!"

Wood had finished tidying his broom up by this point and extended his hand to Tonks, who was still sitting on the grass. She hopped up onto her feet and put her hand around Wood's waist as they started to walk away.

"See ya later, blister in the sun," she waved at Davies, without turning back to look at him.

"I don't know what that means!" He shouted back at her, alone now on the common, watching Wood and Tonks walk off towards the castle.

"Can't say I blame him, though." Tonks grinned at Wood. "Good for Potter, eh?"

"This is my lot in life. I'm surrounded by ridiculous people." Wood sighed.

"Don't pretend you don't love it," She gave him a quick peck on the cheek. "See you in Charms, broom-boy."

Meanwhile
Azkaban

The Dementor wafted gently back and forth amidst the seemingly perpetual torrents of rain. It floated as lazily as a concrete representation of an abstract pattern could float; there were no expectations to guide it besides the vague, disconnected obligation to the oligarchs of Britain and the Aurors who enforced their will. The Aurors did not know the exact location of this Dementor, only that it was supposed to be guarding the perimeter. As such, it was listless, with little purpose other than to simply exist, despite the fact that it had no existence in and of itself. It was a being composed solely of negative space, defined purely by the absence of life, an Escher painting made concrete.

Long before the era of Harry James Potter-Evans-Verres, the 15th century magical scholar, Phillipus Aureolus Theophrastus Bombastus von Hohenheim was credited with, among other things, discovering and proving conclusive means of slaying a dementor: the complete and utter extermination of life. Indeed, it was a popular theory at the time that the ancient Atlanteans had fled from this world because it had become overcome with the Specters of Death, and only by destroying the world could they truly save it. As it were, there was about as much truth behind that origin story as there was behind the theory that Atlanteans were interstellar travelers.

But as it stood, no one had managed to provide a demonstration of Paracelsus' conjecture. And as with many magical truths, the knowledge of it faded from the minds of the wizened over the centuries, until it was replaced with daft, but comforting superstition. The Dementors, responding to the shift in perception and expectation, obliged through no volition of their own.

When the violently pulsating light pierced the waves of rainfall, a new set of expectations, a new perspective took precedent over all others.

And the Dementor cowered.

Leave us... Please.

NO.

Leave us... it is our nature. Do not wish it, but cannot cease.

COME.

Leave us...

COME, OR END.

There was no conflict of expectations, there could be none. The Patronus that stood before it could brook no compromise, it would accept nothing less than complete and total dominance over the cowering wretch before it. In any compromise between good and evil, it is only death that can win, and so there was no compromise. It submitted itself fully and entirely, shrugging off the bonds that kept it within the confines of Azkaban and sped off into the distance, a specter of Death following its Master.

Moments Later
The Black Lake

"Okay, so remember what I said... you're going to be safe, even though it might be scary. Well, no, it will be scary. Really, really scary. But I want you to tell me exactly what you see."

Rainbow Dash was gawking at the hooded, black-cloaked figure that was cowering in fear at the edge of the lake. "He doesn't look that scary. In fact, I think he's more scared of us..."

"Don't let that deceive you. This... thing is..." Harry was internally debating whether it would make more sense to explain the nature of the Dementor to Rainbow Dash, or to let her come to the conclusion on her own.

Rainbow Dash stuck a finger up to her lips and shooshed him. "Shhh. Don't ruin the surprise."

Harry shrugged at her. His Patronus was lurking in the trees, out of sight of Rainbow Dash, but keeping firmly in the light of sight of the cowering Dementor.

STAND, it commanded.

Visibly shuddering, the Dementor rose and turned towards Rainbow Dash.

"So, I just... what, look at it?"

Harry nodded, gravely.

"Okay, here I go," she said skeptically, taking a few steps forward, completely unaware as to the nature of the hole in the world before her. She stretched her hand out to touch the hood of the cloak, gently pulling it away from the creature.

And then the world went mad.

Chapter 11: Endgame

The Forbidden Forest
Earlier the Previous Day

"My younger students," Professor Quirrell said in a loud, strong voice. "I know this probably seems very fearsome to some of you… Especially those of you that opted not to participate in our extracurricular activities. It is the custom of Hogwarts that grades are given in the second week of June, but in my case… they made an exception."

The Defense Professor smiled his familiar dry smile and continued, "I know you are worried that you are not prepared for this exam, that my lessons have not covered this material, and I quite forgot to mention that it was approaching… though you should have known it would come in time.

"Your full year grade depends on the outcome of this battle. As with life, nothing else matters if you fail the most important test."

Students started murmuring among themselves in hushed, worried whispers. Quirrell remained silent until the whisperers realized they were interrupting him, and hurriedly shut up.

"I understand that we have some visitors from another school, and although their purpose was never made entirely clear, it seems they have taken it upon themselves to become teachers of sorts: offering advice, smoothing over disagreements, mediating disputes, or in some cases…" As he spoke, he looked pointedly at Fluttershy, and then a gaggle of Slytherin first-years. "…Ending them decisively.

"It should be clear from the fact that I had accepted the post of Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher, that I enjoy my life in relative solitude. There are few who will truly mourn me, and none who depend upon me. Of course, I have seen firsthand that there are many who would fight far more valiantly to defend others than themselves. That people are far more willing to gamble with their own lives than with others.

"People shun the cold, dispassionate, utilitarian moral calculus of sacrifice, yet are willing to do so when it is someone else that they would protect."

"I confess that it had not occurred to provide instruction on this matter, how to recognize it, how to overcome it, how to manipulate it. However, this final exam allows me to rectify that wrong:

"You will engage in a battle. The remainder of Sunshine Regiment, along with those who had chosen not to participate, will be distributed amongst the Dragon Army and Chaos Legion.

"Both armies will be given something to protect, both literally and metaphorically. Your grade and the grade of your classmates will depend not only on your team's performance but on your ability to protect.

"Of our Beauxbatons visitors, only four are healthy enough to participate in such a task, so the four of them have been divided between your two armies."

He gestured towards Rainbow Dash and Applejack, "The Gryffindor with the questionably multi-colored hair, and the Hufflepuff with the out-of-place accent shall be assigned to Chaos Legion."

He then looked towards Fluttershy and Pinkie Pie, "The Ravenclaw with the seemingly boundless enthusiasm for all things trivial, along with the Slytherin with an unusual proclivity for defenseless creatures…" He looked again at Fluttershy, "And from what I understand, she gets quite protective of them…"

He turned back to the students. "These are your wards, your charges, your Protectorates. Your goal is simply to find them, and escort them back here to the starting point, the Sanctuary." He gestured to the edges of the clearing, where a translucent, slightly glowing blue circle on the ground surrounded them. "Within the bounds of this Sanctuary, no magic is to be used. If you break this rule, you shall forfeit the game.

"If you survive, and your team wins, you shall earn an Outstanding. Alternately, if you do not survive, and your team wins, you shall only earn an Acceptable.

"On the other hand, if you survive but your team simply loses, you shall earn an Exceed Expectations. Given that death is the default assumed outcome for all of you, eventually, that assignation is not entirely inappropriate.

"However, if you survive and your team has failed your Protectorates by allowing them to be eliminated, you shall earn a grade of Poor. And if you should be so unfortunate as to not survive while your team has failed, then you will find yourself with a grade of Troll.

"Finally, and perhaps anticlimactically, should you not survive and your team simply loses without allowing your Protectorates to be eliminated, you shall earn a grade of Dreadful."

The students were looking amongst each other, clearly somewhat confused by the circuitous rules and scoring mechanism. Harry, on the other hand, was frowning while the professor continued, "The game shall end in one of two conditions: when a team's Protectorates crosses the bounds of the Sanctuary, or when the allotted time of two hours has elapsed. Both ending conditions come with certain consequences.

"When the Protectorates enter the Sanctuary, any members of your own team who are not within the bounds of the Sanctuary shall forfeit, so as to prevent the protectorates from simply making a mad dash towards the Sanctuary. Similarly, any members of the opposing team who are within the Sanctuary when their team loses will forfeit, so as to discourage taking advantage of the protection afforded by the Sanctuary. If the two hours elapse without a victor, then all four Protectorates, along with anyone not within the bounds of the Sanctuary, shall forfeit."

The confused looks on the students' faces only deepened, as did Harry's concentration. "The countdown shall begin shortly. But one final note; I have also cast the Incantation of Babel upon both teams to prevent communication between the teams and the Protectorates. Any attempt at communication will result in abject nonsense, so you have been warned."

With a curt nod, he began to walk towards the edge of the dais, then added, almost as an afterthought in response to the countless faces staring blankly up at him. "As you all should know by this point, I do not repeat myself, so if you have any questions about the rules, then I would hope that your teammates have paid more attention than you."

Draco was pacing, almost manically. "Ok. Nobody expected this, this test. So there's no way Potter could have prepared for things."

"We think," Zabini added, quite unhelpfully.

"Right. We think. Wait, what?" Draco was hardly listening to the input. "No. We don't think, we know. Professor Quirrell wouldn't give an advantage to anyone, much less Saint Potter."

"Unless he came up with a bunch of alternate strategies just in case something like this happened." Zabini chimed in again.

Draco considered this for a moment. "No, any strategy that he came up with, he would have to rehearse and plot in advance with other people. We would have heard something if Harry had started planning for a battle that was never to come. So, no, I think we're on a level playing field in that regard."

He began pacing again, but the manic shakiness had left his voice and he was speaking with more confidence, "There's no shame in admitting that Potter is more clever. So I think he'll likely come up with something. But magically, we've got him beat in terms of pure strength. But Harry knows that, so he's not going to engage us on those terms."

Dean Thomas piped up. "I was on Chaos Legion before the teams got redistributed. You're right that he's not going to engage us traditionally. But, I think he isn't going to engage us at all."

"Huh?"

"Well, think about it. Harry always talks about the Batman code of ethics."

"The what?"

"Batman. A Muggle superhero. It means, nobody dies. He doesn't have to save you, but he's not going to kill you. I think that's what it is. Every one of us he takes out, that's hurting us in the real world; we're losing marks off our grade. He's not going to want that. He's going to find a way to do it without having a battle at all."

Draco's eyes widened. "Merlin's beard, you're right. They're going to fan out. Probably break off into squads of two, maybe three. He'll order them not to engage if they see us, and they'll scour the woods until they find the Protectorates, and then they'll run like hell back to the Sanctuary."

Pansy raised her hand meekly, but then quickly put it down when she noticed multiple people staring at her. "But if they do that, then everyone else on their team will end up losing. At least, that's what I think the Professor said."

Draco waved this off. "Yes, that's what he said, but it's easy enough to develop a system of communication. Bubblers, magic mirrors, enchanted coins, even smoke signals. They find their Protectorate, they fire off the signal, then they all fall back to the Sanctuary."

"Small squads are going to be pretty weak, easy to pick off." Zabini offered.

"Right, so we need to play to our strengths. We stay together, sweep the forest as one unit."

"They'll be able to cover a lot more ground than us. They will find their charges before we do," Zabini argued.

"They might. But they don't just need to find them, they need to escort them safely back to the Sanctuary. Their Protectorates and their entire army. His troops will be spread out across the forest. No matter where we are, as long as we converge on the Sanctuary as soon as the endgame begins, we will reach it before the remainder of their army. Potter won't sacrifice the few to save the many. Batman ethics, as you say. He will wait until every last man is safe, and until then, he'll be vulnerable."

Zabini was nodding and didn't offer a rebuttal. Ron Weasley was considering this as well, "But how will we know the endgame has begun?"

"That… That is where I'm hoping someone in this army can help because I don't have any clue how we should do that."

Crickets.

Birds chirping.

Then silence.

Until the soft, vaguely distant voice of Luna Lovegood cast a pebble into the otherwise still pond, "We look for Wrackspurts."

"Wrackspurts?" Ron asked, incredulously. "What next? I suppose we should also look for Nargles in the mistletoe?"

Draco spat, "Can it, Weasley. Unless you have a better idea." Ron said nothing, so Draco pressed the point. "Well, do you?"

Ron looked at his feet. "No, I was just saying… Wait! What if we just wait by the Sanctuary, wait for them to come back, and then ambush them?"

Draco rolled his eyes. "We want to win, not just keep Potter from winning. How do we expect to find our charges if we're sitting here on our thumbs waiting for Potter and his army?"

"I, uh… well…"

Draco cut him off. "Luna, continue."

"Ron is right, you know," she added, not seeming to pay attention.

"He what?"

"Mistletoe. It's full of Nargles," she smiled and started twirling her hair a bit.

More crickets.

More birds chirping.

More silence.

Draco didn't want to interrupt whatever train of thought he assumed, or hoped, was running through Luna's mind, so he waited patiently.

"But, now that I think of it, they only come out when it's Christmas, or when love is in the air. So we don't need to worry about them." She nodded at Ron and then turned back to Draco. "If you want to see someone who's wearing an invisibility cloak, you don't look for them, you look for the Wrackspurts floating around their head. So we fill the forest with Wrackspurts."

"I don't know about you, Luna, but I didn't pack my bag full of Wrackspurts for this battle," Ron groaned, trying to save face by finding a flaw in Luna's plan.

Draco sighed and grit his teeth. "She's speaking metaphorically. Now. Shut. It."

Luna nodded, and then let out a small sound of affirmation. "Come to think of it, I did bring my Wrackspurt jar." She fiddled through her pack and pulled out what appeared to be a thoroughly empty glass jar, sealed with a wax and metal lid. She shook the jar a bit, then cooed at its contents. "But there aren't nearly enough of them. No, this is what I was thinking."

She hooked her wand in the air, making a delicate threading motion, and a thin, luminous stream of iridescent light extruded from the end. She guided it around the trunk of the tree, then continued stretching the silvery thread across a small clearing, and then wrapped it around another tree. She gave it a quick tug to test its strength, and when satisfied, she pointed her wand at the string and then whispered:

"Xaphod Beeblebrox."

She turned to Ron. "Walk through it, you'll see."

Ron looked ahead with great apprehension, "It's not going to… it's not gonna hurt me, is it?"

"No, of course not."

Ron started taking a few steps towards the thread, and Luna spoke again, half to herself, "Although my father did say that the famous shapeshifter, Andre the Androgynous, used that spell to change his gender…"

Ron froze, then gaped.

"Don't worry, I think he just made that up to sell Quibblers. He does that a lot, you know?"

"You don't say…" Ron was not entirely comforted by this addendum, but in absence of any other suggestions, he continued to step forward until he reached the silvery thread. Bracing himself, he walked forward, his muscles growing tenser as the line became more taut. Finally, when he could handle the suspense no longer, he took a quick step forward and the line snapped, sending a fantastic shower of glitter and sparks into the air, visible at least ten to fifteen feet above the tree line.

"If we string these up throughout the forest, starting at the Sanctuary and working outward, they might be able to avoid breaking them if they were treading carefully and softly. But if they were making a headlong rush back to the base, they'd be bound to give their position away."

Draco was nodding, deep in thought. "So if we start by making our way to the Sanctuary, then slowly working our way outward… I think that we need to go in a spiral pattern to make sure we cover all side." He did a bit of mental math. "As long as we work quickly, we should be able to cover most of the ground of the battlefield within an hour, maybe an hour and a half. So one of two things will happen, we'll either find our charges before Potter does, or sparks will start shooting out from around the forest, in which case we make a run for it back to the Sanctuary, dispatch Potter's army, and continue our search."

He turned towards the rest of the army. "It seems an easy enough spell to learn. We have 10 minutes until the battle starts, I want you all to practice it. Once you've mastered it, fall into position, and we'll start plotting our course.

Harry paced, almost manically. "Draco's going to know, at minimum, that we don't plan to engage. So he's going to bunch up, try to leverage his superior firepower and superior numbers. But… thanks to Angela, here," he gave big thumbs up to Angela Ziegler, who blushed, "We have a great combination of spells that can temporarily pause the battle, hopefully for just long enough for them to listen.

"Malleus Descendum will knock them off their feet, and then, what was it again? 'The Ultimate Mercy'? It will… well… Angela, why don't you explain it?"

She kicked the dirt self-consciously but addressed the crowd. "It casts in a wide area. Anyone who is laying on the ground, whether they're unconscious, petrified, sleeping, or just laying down… It lifts them up a bit, and it bathes them in a barrier that doesn't let low-level spells either in or out. It's not going to help much against Avada Kedavra, but it would stop a Somnium or even a Stupefy."

Harry nodded with satisfaction. "Right, and in that time, that's when we try to get through to them. Shout, 'Merlin says, the rules are flawed, we all can win.' There are ex-Chaos Legionnaires in there, they'll know what 'Merlin says' means. They won't know what the rest of it means, but it might make them pause long enough to listen to us.

"You're permitted to fight to defend yourself, but under no circumstances are you to shoot to kill. Trip them up, immobilize them, but don't put them to sleep. Our goal is to win, not make the other group lose. If you make contact, send a message to the group. If your partner falls, send up green sparks in the air so we can track your location. When and if you locate the charges, send a message to the group and immediately fall back to the Sanctuary. If you come under attack and have our Protectorates with you, send red sparks into the air, and we will instead converge on your location."

Harry exhaled. "And finally, if you successfully convince Draco and his army of the fact that there's a bloody stupid loophole in these rules and we can all get an Outstanding, then fire blue sparks into the air, and there will be much rejoicing."

Harry's army nodded, solemnly, and began to break into pairs.

"Come on, get a move on. I hear Draco's army in the distance!" Harry whispered sharply at Applejack and Rainbow Dash. Applejack, in turn, gave a sidelong glance to Rainbow Dash.

Harry waved his hand back and forth. "What are you waiting for?"

Rainbow Dash rolled her eyes, and spoke in a hoarse voice that sounded more like a washed up pop signer than the more feminine rasp of her own voice. "I hope you particularly enjoy the incredible crassness of the moment when we try to squeeze an extra syllable into the fourth line."

Harry shook his head in frustration. "Damnit. Forgot about the Incantation of Babel. I wonder how far its effects extend… Can you understand hand signals?"

Harry's start down the rabbit hole was interrupted by his companion, the wispy blonde little Hufflepuff that Applejack recognized as Angela Ziegler. She spoke in an authoritative voice that seemed to fit her, despite her diminutive frame. "Harry, are you ready?"

Harry looked off in the other direction sharply, listening intently. Rainbow dash leaned in and she could hear the noise as well. Footfall, and lots of it. It was coming from the direction of the clearing opposite them.

With sudden urgency in his movement, Harry charged forward. Angela followed a few meters behind, with a bright golden tether of light emanating from her wand having attached itself to Harry. She was whispering something to herself as she ran… "I'll enjoy the quiet while it lasts…"

There was a sense of strange desperation in Harry's movement. His companion followed swiftly thereafter and the noise of the footfalls grew louder as he closed the distance to the clearing. Just as Harry reached the edge, a large group of students emerged, led by a boy with a pointed face and slick, platinum blonde hair.

With one final effort, Harry charged forward, holding his wand as if it were a hammer and then shouted in his own voice, "Malleus Descendum!"

Harry was propelled forward with unnatural speed, and when his wand connected with the ground, a shockwave was sent towards the group of other students. When it hit them, they were all swept off their feet and Angela came charging in afterward, holding her wand high in the air and yelled, "Helden Sterben Nicht!"

The battlefield was bathed in a blinding, golden light.

Dragon Army was desperately trying to reorient itself, many of their members trying to fire curses that fizzled unceremoniously in the golden light, but realizing that it was a futile effort, they reserved their magic and prepared for the effects of the barrier to wear off.

In that brief moment of calm, Harry shouted to the crowd. "MERLIN SAYS, THE RULES ARE FLAWED, WE ALL CAN WIN!"

And then both he and Angela tossed down his wands and held their hands up in the air in a clear gesture of surrender.

By that point, the barrier had faded away, and not sensing any immediate threat, the entirety of Dragon Army looked to Draco for direction.

Draco's mind was racing. The Professor's rules seemed to be solid. There was a very good chance this was a trap, a ruse designed to buy time until the rest of his army could arrive. But their tripwires hadn't been sprung; if Chaos Legion was closing in on them, they were doing it slowly and methodically. So he had time.

"Hands in the air. Keep your hands up. Walk away from your wands."

Harry did precisely what he was told, and the moment he felt he wasn't in imminent danger, the words tumbled out of his mouth as fast as he could think them. "Listen to me. The rules are flawed, there's a loophole. The game ends when the Protectorates cross the boundary and if everyone is in the Sanctuary and both teams Protectorates cross at exactly the same time, the game ends, everyone is alive, and we all satisfy the win condition and all we need to do is figure out a way to get the four of them to cross the boundary simultaneously but I don't really know how to do that since simultaneity is really just a macroscopic phenomenon and depends entirely on your reference frame, but Magic really doesn't seem to give a damn about quantum mechanics and-"

"Harry. Harry. HARRY! Shut up, I can't think." Draco was closing his eyes in concentration, then after a brief moment of silence, called out to his army. "Dragon Army, stand down!"

For a brief time, the only sound was the rustle of robes as wands were being put away.

"Now, Harry, please explain what the hell you are on about."

"Gladly. But first, would you mind shooting some blue sparks in the air?"

Chapter 15: Liberate Tutemet Ex Inferis

The last chamber was illuminated in lights of soft gold, and the stone walls were of gentle white and faced with marble.

In the center of the room stood a simple and unornamented golden frame, and within the frame was a portal to another gold-illuminated room, beyond whose door which lay another Potions chamber; that was what Harry's brain told him. The Mirror's transformation of light was so perfect that conscious thought was required to deduce that the room inside the frame was only a reflection, rather than a portal. (Though it might have been easier to intuit if Harry hadn't been invisible, just then.)

The Mirror did not touch the ground; the golden frame had no feet. It didn't look like it was hovering; it looked like it was fixed in place, more solid and more motionless than the walls themselves, like it was nailed to the reference frame of the Earth's motion.

From behind, the golden frame appeared solid, showing no reflections, and at the Professor's request, Harry finally removed his invisibility cloak. Upon seeing that the Mirror stayed in place, the Professor breathed a sigh of relief and entered the chamber alongside the five witches, careful not to allow himself to be reflected. He examined the frame from the sides and waved his hand dismissively.

Upon the center of the golden back had appeared a sequence of runes in no known alphabet, black absences of light in small lines and curves, arranged in a level horizontal row.

"How old is this Mirror?" Harry said in almost a whisper.

"Nobody knows, Mr. Potter." The Defense Professor reached out his fingers toward the runes, a look of something like reverence on his face; but his fingers did not touch the gold. "But my guess is the same as yours, I think. It is said, in certain legends that may or may not be fabrications, that this Mirror reflects itself perfectly and therefore its existence is absolutely stable. So stable that the Mirror was able to survive when every other effect of Atlantis was undone, all its consequences severed from Time." The Defense Professor let his hand fall.

Even in the middle of everything else, Harry felt the awe, if that was true. The golden frame gleamed no brighter than before, for all the revelation; but you could imagine it going back, and back, into a civilization that had been made to never be... "What - does the Mirror do, exactly?"

"An excellent question," said Professor Quirrell. "The answer is in the runes that are written upon the Mirror's golden frame. Read them to me."

"They're not in any alphabet I recognize. They look like randomly oriented chicken-scratches drawn by Tolkien elves."

He tried obvious tricks like looking at the runes upside down or backwards, then he tried some degree of frequency analysis to see if it was a simple substitution cipher... but his train of thought was interrupted by Pinkie Pie fastidiously scrutinizing the letters, then declaring with confidence, "I show not your face, but your coherent extrapolated volition!"

It clicked.

She was right. A chill ran down Harry's spine. As he examined the runes closer, he found he was able to extract meaning from them when previously there had been none. It still wasn't in any language he could recognize, but it was meaning. 'noitilov detalo partxe tnere hoc ruoy tu becafruoy ton wo hsi'. Harry knew what the rune for noitilov meant. It meant noitilov. And the next runes said to detalo the noitilov until it reached partxe, then keep the part that was both tnere and hoc. And somehow, both Harry and the Professor believed her translation was right, and that belief felt like knowledge.

The Professor stared at her in silence, the look on his face inscrutable.

Pinkie shrugged, "What, you can't read ∑∫ỹriȱŋ Runes?"

Applejack cocked an eyebrow, "Pinkie, I don't think any of us canread Alleria Runes."

Fluttershy examined the runes as well, comprehension dawning on her, "No, Applejack, it's '∑∫ỹriȱŋ'. Don't you remember when Twilight hosted that seminar on Ancient Equestrian Languages? We each picked one or two, you learned how to write in Zebasi, remember?"

"Oh yeah, the farming folk! Let me guess, Pinkie, you learned all of them?"

Pinkie nodded, nonchalantly, and gave an off-hand "Mm-hmm."

The Professor was ignoring the chatter, and whispering to himself, "Yes... Your extrapolated volition... The Mirror displays you with what you actually want, not with what you say you want." He turned his attention up towards Harry, "I have wandered the world and encountered many stories that are not often heard. Most of them seemed to me to be lies, but a few had the ring of history rather than storytelling. Upon a wall of metal in a place where no one had come for centuries, I found written the claim that some Atlanteans foresaw their world's end, and sought to forge a device of great power to avert the inevitable catastrophe. If that device had been completed, the story claimed, it would have become an absolutely stable existence that could withstand the channeling of unlimited magic in order to grant wishes. And also - this was said to be the vastly harder task - the device would somehow avert the inevitable catastrophes any sane person would expect to follow from that premise. The Mirror's most characteristic power is to create alternate realms of existence, though these realms are only as large in size as what can be seen within the Mirror; it is known that people and other objects can be stored therein. It is claimed, for example, that phoenixes came into our world from a realm that was evoked inside this Mirror."

Harry was frowning, despite being impressed at the scope of the Mirror's power. Professor Quirrel began to frown at Harry's frowning. "What is it?"

"It's just... well... The Headmaster and I had something of a confrontation, an argument. And he showed me, in no uncertain terms, using a Phoenix, of all things, that he would be the one to remove the Stone from the Mirror."

"I see," said Professor Quirrell. "Oh, dear. I wish you had thought to mention this to me a good deal earlier. This eliminates an entire class of hypotheses. You see, the other great difficulty of the Mirror is that the rule by which it treats those reflected will disregard external forces, such as False Memories or a Confundus Charm. The Mirror reflects only those forces arising from within the person themselves, the states of mind they arrive at through their own choices; so it is said in several places. Dumbledore has access to some unusual power of Divination; that much I deduced long ago. He made too many nonsensical moves, and the paths by which they worked out in his favor were too ridiculous. So if he somehow knows that he is the one to remove the Stone..."

"Um, Professor?" Harry raised his hand, and then realizing how silly that was, put it down quickly. "About that. In his effort to defeat Lord Voldemort, the Headmaster read every single entry in the Hall of Prophecy."

Silence.

Ringing, almost unending silence.

"Sounds boring," Rainbow Dash yawned.

The Professor did not react to this piece of information, at least not outwardly, and simply said, "I see," He paced around the perimeter of the Mirror's reflect and continued to speak. "The Mirror's instructions cannot be shaped to react to individual people. So it is not possible for Dumbledore to command this Mirror, 'only give the Stone to Dumbledore'. Dumbledore cannot state, 'Only give the Stone to one who wishes to give it to Nicholas Flamel'. There is in the Mirror a blindness such as philosophers have attributed to ideal justice; it must treat all who come before it by the same rule, whatever rule may be in force. Thus, there must be some rule for reaching the Stone's hiding-place which anyone can invoke. And yet, if prophecy has foretold..."

"Arguendo," Harry said. "We're not sure what's necessary to retrieve the Stone. Ignoring the bit about prophecy... by the rules you state, a sufficient condition should involve Albus Dumbledore in a state of mind where they believe that the Dark Lord has been defeated, that the threat is over, and that it is time to take out the Stone and give it back to Nicholas Flamel. We aren't sure which part of that person's state of mind, let's say Dumbledore's, will be the necessary part but under those conditions, Dumbledore's entire state of mind will be sufficient."

"Reasonable," said Professor Quirrell. "So?"

"The corresponding strategy," Harry said carefully, "is to mimic Dumbledore's state of mind under those conditions, in as much detail as possible, while standing in front of the mirror. And this state of mind must have been produced by internal forces, not external ones. Thereby fulfilling both the rules of the Mirror and Dumbledore's insight into the future of seeing himself remove the stone."

The Professor was nodding intently. "But how are we to get that without Legilimency or the Confundus Charm, both of which would certainly be external - ha. I see." Professor Quirrell's ice-pale eyes were suddenly piercing. "You suggest that I Confund myself, as you cast that hex upon yourself during your first day in Battle Magic. So that it is an internal force and not an external one, a state of mind that comes about through only my own choices."

The Professor stood a moment in calculation, then commanded Harry to put on his Cloak of Invisibility. "There is no way beneath the heavens that the Mirror is not meant as a trap. That is to say, it's a trap for Lord Voldemort. Only it can't be a trap for him personally. It is a trap for some generalizable quality of Lord Voldemort that triggers it. And so when the Confundus Charm expires, and the Mirror observes the deception, I believe that will be, in Dumbledore's mind, what you call 'sufficient' conditions to Voldemort's state of mind. After all, Dumbledore would only consider one person clever enough to bypass both the Mirror and what is foretold by Prophecy."

Without conscious awareness, Harry was frowning hard at the Mirror's golden back. "What are you getting at?"

"Or perhaps two people... Lord Voldemort, and you. If he sees that you were the one who retrieved the Stone, or at least that you had a hand in the plot, he would, I think, be very disinclined to spring whatever trap has been lain. So you must stand by my side, ready to reveal yourself at the proper moment. The rest of you," he gestured at the witches, "may observe from behind the Mirror."

Then Professor Quirrell pointed with his wand, and a shimmering circle appeared around where Harry was standing on the floor. This, Professor Quirrell said, would soon become a Greater Circle of Concealment, by which nothing within that circle could be heard or seen from the outside. Harry would not be able to make himself apparent to the false Dumbledore by taking off the Cloak, nor by shouting.

Then Professor Quirrell's robes became black tinged with gold, such robes as Dumbledore might wear upon a formal occasion; and Professor Quirrell pointed his own wand at his head.

Professor Quirrell stayed motionless for a long time, still holding his wand to his head. His eyes were closed in concentration.

And then Professor Quirrell said, "Confundus."

At once the expression of the man standing there changed; he blinked a few times as though confused, lowering his wand.

A deep weariness spread over the face Professor Quirrell had worn; without any visible change his eyes seemed older, the few lines in his face calling attention to themselves.

His lips were set in a sad smile.

Without any hurry, the man quietly walked over to the Mirror, as though he had all the time in the world.

He crossed into the Mirror's range of reflection without anything happening and stared into the surface.

What the man might be seeing there, Harry could not tell; to Harry, it seemed that the flat, perfect surface still reflected the room behind it, like a portal to another place.

"Ariana," breathed the man. "Mother, father. And you, my brother, it is done."

The man stood still, as if listening.

"Yes, done," the man said. "Voldemort came before this mirror and was trapped by Merlin's method. He is only one more sealed horror now."

Again the listening stillness.

"I would that I could obey you, my brother, but it is better this way." The man bowed his head. "He is denied his death, forever; that vengeance is terrible enough."

"It is time to give back the Philosopher's Stone," said the man who thought he was Dumbledore. "It must go back into Master Flamel's keeping, now."

Listening stillness.

"No," said the man, "Master Flamel has kept it safe these many years from all who would seek immortality, and I think it will be safest in his hands... no, Aberforth, I do think his intentions are good."

"Destroy it?" said the man. "Maybe. I am not sure it can be destroyed, or Master Flamel would have done it long since. I think, many times, that he has regretted making it... Aberforth, I promised him, and we are not so ancient or so wise ourselves. The Philosopher's Stone must go back into the keeping of the one who made it."

And Harry's breath stopped.

The man was holding an irregular chunk of scarlet glass in his left hand, the size perhaps of Harry's thumb from fingernail to the first joint. The sheened surface of the scarlet glass made it seem wet; the appearance was of blood, suspended in time and made into a jagged surface.
"Thank you, my brother," the man said quietly.

And then -

"No, Ariana," the man said, smiling gently, "I fear I must go now. Be patient, my dearest, it will be soon enough that I join you in truth... why? Why, I am not sure why I must go... when I hold the Stone I am to step aside from the Mirror and wait for Master Flamel to contact me, but I am not sure why I need to step aside from the Mirror to do that..." The man sighed. "Ah, I am getting old. It is well this dreadful war ended when it did. I suppose there is no harm if I speak to you for a time, my dearest, if you wish it so."

The man who thought he was Dumbledore was mostly nodding patiently, sometimes replying to his dearest sister. Sometimes the man cast an uneasy look to one side; as if feeling a strong impulse to go, but suppressing that impulse with the great patience and politeness and concern for his sister that Professor Quirrell imagined Albus Dumbledore having.

Harry saw it the instant the Confundus wore off, and the man's expression changed, becoming again the face of Professor Quirrell.

And in the same instant, the Mirror changed, no longer showing Harry the reflection of the room, showing instead the form of the real Albus Dumbledore, as though he were standing just behind the Mirror and visible through it.

The real Dumbledore's face was set, and grim.

"Hello, Tom," said Albus Dumbledore.

A presence invaded the air around Harry, a crawling sensation all over his flesh Professor Quirrell's magic passed very close to his skin. The Cloak of Invisibility was torn away from him, and the shimmering black Cloak flew away from him, to his left. Professor Quirrell caught it, and swiftly drew it over himself; in less than a second, he had pulled down the Cloak's hood over his head and disappeared.

Albus Dumbledore staggered, as though some essential support had been removed from him.

"Harry Potter," the Headmaster breathed. "What are you doing here? "

Harry stared at the image of Albus Dumbledore, on whose face utter shock and utter dismay were warring.

"Headmaster, listen, this is my fault," Harry spoke with urgent warning. "The Professor is dying. I can't let that happen. I know what you showed me, and I know this is cheating, and I know you probably disapprove. But the Stone exists. I understand its limitations, I know that it can't be used to save the world, but it can at least be used to help save one life!"

Dumbledore was shaking his head desperately. "No," said Albus Dumbledore. "No, no, NO!"

Into the hand of the Albus Dumbledore flew from his sleeve his long, dark-grey wand, and in his other hand, as though from nowhere, appeared a short rod of dark stone.

Albus Dumbledore gazed distantly spoke, "Listen to me, and know that I speak not only to you." During the pause, Harry looked nervously to his left, where he assumed the invisible Professor still stood. "There is a prophecy that begins, 'ON THE LONGEST DAY OF THE THOUSANDTH YEAR, THE STARS WILL AID IN HER ESCAPE, AND SHE WILL BRING ABOUT NIGHTTIME ETERNAL.' This branch of the prophecy has already come to pass, but the prophecy itself continues."

The words of the prophecy that Dumbledore uttered carried with them an inexplicable ring of truth. The diction, the pacing, the very presentation made it clear which words were Dumbledore's own and which were those laid down by the Prophets of old, as plainly as if it were written text that had been italicized. As he spoke, the sense of power that prickled across Harry's skin grew increasingly oppressive and uncomfortable.

"It foretells that 'the Decimation will be at hand, in this time, wands will turn to sticks in the hands of the will-workers' and that 'the very stars in the heavens will be torn asunder'. And it speaks of an 'unlikely friend who has tempted the one marked by lightning'. That friend must 'bring the stone through the gate thrown open by the one who is Bound by the Dark Lord'."

The building sense of power rose to an unbearable peak. Dumbeldore's form began to waver, to crumble away; he struggled to speak his final thoughts, which were clipped and distorted. Harry could only make out the words "redemption" and "magic." In his last moments, Dumbledore threw both the wand and the rod violently aside, and with that, both the sense of power and Dumbledore's form faded into dust.

The Mirror returned to showing the ordinary reflection of a gold-lit room of white stone, without any trace of where Albus Dumbledore had been.

Sydney, Australia

Dumbledore observed the tearful reunion from a respectful distance; Bellatrix Black, Lesath Lestrange, and Narcissa, Lucius and Draco Malfoy, temporarily blind to the rest of the world, content in that one small moment to simply exist in each other's company.

The reverie was soon interrupted by the small voice of Lesath, whose attention was focused on Albus Dumbledore. "Is that... is that normal?" Dumbledore's head was lashing back and forth at an unnatural speed, as if shifting through dimensions, through time.

Draco looked up, slowly in confusion as Dumbledore spoke to someone a world away. "Harry Potter," the Headmaster breathed. "What are you doing here?"

A brief pause. Dumbledore was shaking his head desperately. "No," said Albus Dumbledore. "No, no, NO!"

Albus Dumbledore looked at Draco and spoke intently, "Listen to me, and know that I speak not only to you. There is a prophecy that begins, 'ON THE LONGEST DAY OF THE THOUSANDTH YEAR, THE STARS WILL AID IN HER ESCAPE, AND SHE WILL BRING ABOUT NIGHTTIME ETERNAL.' This branch of the prophecy has already come to pass, but the prophecy itself continues."

Draco turned and looked nervously as Bellatrix Black. The words of the prophecy that Dumbledore uttered carried with them an inexplicable ring of truth.

"It foretells that 'the Decimation will be at hand, in this time, wands will turn to sticks in the hands of the will-workers' and that 'the very stars in the heavens will be torn asunder'. And it speaks of an 'unlikely friend who has tempted the one marked by lightning'. That friend must 'bring the stone through the gate thrown open by the one who is Bound by the Dark Lord'."

Dumbeldore's form began to waver, to crumble away; he struggled to speak his final thoughts, which were clipped and distorted. Draco could only make the words "redemption" and "friendship." In his last moments, Dumbledore threw both the wand and the rod violently aside, which disappeared to a place unknown, and with that, Dumbledore's form faded into dust

The room was now empty, except for the extended Lestrange-Black-Malfoy family. The only remaining trace of Albus Dumbledore was a pair of artifacts that lay on the floor: An ornate ring set with a brilliant sapphire, engraved with a stylized set of goat horns, and a delicate glass necklace; a collection of five or six interconnected bubbles.

Draco immediately recognized the nature of the artifacts, they were tokens of Forbearance; the Transfigured and therefore eternally preserved bodily remains of Wizards from families who still respected the ancient customs, held in abeyance until the heirs of Atlantis could carry them to the eternal day-night. It was an enchantment powered by an unending chain of Magic, passed down from heir to heir, scion to scion, a web reinforced through the bonds of the interconnected families and friendships of Wizardkind. He had long stared at the collection of objects on the mantle of the Malfoy family Oblatorium, and the ring and necklace carried with them the unmistakable touch of that same magic.

No Wizard family of honor would allow such magic to fail, even if it had belonged to their worst enemy, even if Albus Dumbledore had not redeemed himself by returning Narcissa Malfoy to the world of the living. Draco kneeled down and quickly began to chant the ritual,

Listen to the wind blow, down comes the night
Running in the shadows, damn your love, damn your lies
Break the silence, damn the dark, damn the light-

He did not have a chance to complete the ritual, however, as the objects faded to dust underneath his fingers.

Somehow, though, Draco did not experience a feeling of loss or hopelessness as he should have. Inexplicably, he felt a great sense of joy, of love, of reunion and hope.

The End of Time, or, The Beginning of Time

Blackness.

Nothing but blackness.

No.

That was not strictly accurate. Black implied a color; in the additive sense, it implied the presence of all colors.

This was nothingness.

Nothing but nothingness.

No.

There wasn't Nothing. Somewhere in the distance, Albus Dumbledore could hear something. Despite there being no substance through which to carry sound waves, despite having no corporeal body with which to intercept those vibrations, he could hear.

He could hear the distinct sound of music playing.

Was that… David Bowie?

No, not David Bowie. The music was familiar, but the voice... the voice was definitely not David Bowie. The voice was, in fact, quite off-key and pitchy.

"Though nothing, will keep us together... We could steal time, just for one day! We can be heroes, forever and ever. What d'you - Sweet Faustian Bubbles, how long have you been standing there listening for, you little interloper?"

The singing presence instantiated suddenly. It, like Dumbledore, did not have a corporeal form, but it was definitely there.

"I was banished here moments ago, from my perspective." Dumbledore spoke through his non-existent vocal cords, "Though from yours, I suspect that I have always been here and that I will always be here."

"Oh, posh. Why does everyone assume that Time works like that? You and your silly linear brains! Of course, Time has a direction here! How else would you be experiencing this conversation? It's not a straight line, of course, it looks a bit more like this."

A scrawling, loopy collection of lines instantiated in the nothingness, which when all was said and done, looked strangely like a stylized, cursive signature of the name "Jeremy Bearimy". A dot appeared over the "i", which then expanded in size until it encompasses the entirety of their non-existence.

"And we... are here. On that dot."

There was no longer nothingness; it had been replaced by infinite everythingness. Which, as it were, was not that different from nothingness, at least until Dumbledore turned around and saw that the disembodied voice now had a tangible form:

A tall, lanky creaturethat looked like a patchwork amalgam of a dragon, a horse, a lion, an eagle, a goat... And that was just what Dumbledore was able to count.

"You can call me Discord. You must be Albus Dumbledore. Or, at least, you must have been Albus Dumbledore. But now..." Discord looked around in confusion. "Where are you? Oh, gosh, what a rude host I have been! Giving myself tangibility and leaving you to the depressing confines of abstraction."

Discord snapped his finger, and Dumbledore appeared, not as a human wizard, but as a unicorn with a slate-gray coat and a prodigious beard. His new form seemed strangely aged, and on his hindquarters, a symbol was emblazoned: a deep cobalt spiral, decorated with several stars in a shade of gray lighter than his coat.

"Much better," Discord crooned. "Much better than a voice floating in mid-air, and certainly loads better than a withered old man with a questionable fashion sense. I mean, squashed mushroom hats, really?"

Dumbledore observed with mild amusement, "I daresay that this form seems a trite more noble than the body I inhabited mere minutes ago."

"That's the spirit! Now, we won't be alone for too long, a great Transmigration is about to begin. I'm a quite busy pseudo-deity, you know? So much time, so little to do! Wait. Strike that, reverse it. I've got a world to create. Two worlds, really, but we'll save that little spoiler for a later chapter, huh?"

Dumbledore smiled pleasantly with his new body, "I, too, have all the time in the world."

"Yes, I suppose you do. Now look, in a few thousand Bearimies, you're going to have to do me a really, really big favor. So I'm going to do YOU a favor now. I know better than anyone that eternity can be dreadfully boring. So..."

With a dramatic flourish, Discord waved a claw and the pure white everythingness around them split horizontally into two. He lifted his paw upwards, and the top half faded to a deep, midnight blue: the horizon and night sky of this new land. The fingers of his paw and claw twittered in the air as he waved them all around, and stars began to populate the night until there was a universe of constellations above them.

Dumbledore looked upwards. "It is quite beautiful. I had often told myself that I wished I had more time to simply look up to the heavens and stargaze. It seems you have granted that wish for me."

Discord rolled his eyes heavily, "Really? You think the 'favor' I'm doing for you is giving you a sky full of stars to stare at for all of eternity? Try doing that for a Bearimy or two and tell me how interesting you think it is." Discord paced around in a huff, searching through the stars for something. "Sheesh, can't a Draconequus get a bit more credit than that? I mean, really. Stargazing? I'm of half a mind to chuck you back out where you came from!"

Discord trailed off as he scanned the sky intently, and Dumbledore waited patiently. Finally, Discord found what he was looking for and stretched his arms into the sky, which obligingly elongated to an absurd length. After a few moments, they began to quickly retract and it was clear that Discord was holding a pair of stars.

Holding them delicately like two eggs, he cracked each against the ground and gently tore them apart along the resulting fracture. A pair of figures flowed forth from the now-torn stars: firstly, a grey pegasus with a messy blonde mane and a mark upon her flank in the shape of bubbles. And secondly, a goat with deep blue fur and an imposing set of curved, majestic horns. Currently, both appeared to be sleeping soundly.

Dumbledore's eyes went wide. "Are these...?"

Discord smiled, genuinely. "Yes. Now listen, you have no idea how much work that took, so don't get any ideas about asking for more, at least for the time being. I've got a plan in place, in fact, that's what you're going to help me with eventually. But for now, I need to prepare the house for our other guests. Of course, they won't have nearly the same recollection of the past as you three, so do be patient with them." Before Dumbledore was able to ask any further questions about this cryptic warning, Discord gave him a brief "Ta ta!", snapped a claw, and winked out of existence.

The two sleeping figures began to slowly open their eyes, adjusting to their new forms in this new land. The goat was the first to fully rouse himself, and he stood up and looked at the unicorn in front of him.

"Albus?"

"Aberforth..."

"Well, I'll be damned. You did it, you held on to me. I thought you said that ritual was rubbish, for daft, fool purebloods." Aberforth spoke with a grin.

"I have learned, in my old age, that there are many things that at first do not appear to make sense, and it is wise to not dismiss them."

"Wise words, because not a damned bit of this," he looked down at his goat-form. "makes sense. Although, I'm quite fond of this little beard here." Aberforth admired the tuft of fur growing beneath his goat chin for a moment but was unceremoniously interrupted when he was tackled by the newly-awoken pegasus, who gripped him in a tight hug.

"Aberforth! Albus!" she squealed with delight. "Look at me, I can fly!"

Ariana Dumbledore zoomed back and forth between the two of them in pure delight. "I knew you'd do it, Albus, I just knew you would! Oh, this is so exciting! Come on, let's go play!"

Albus Dumbledore bathed in the profound sense of joy, of love, of reunion and hope, and patted his sister on her newfound wings. "Yes, Ariana. I suppose we have some time to play. I suppose we have all the time in the world."

Chapter 16: Follow My Heart Into The Fire

Harry didn't know, then or ever, how long he walked; the light of burning spiderwebs was too dim to read his mechanical watch, and Harry had not thought to look at the time before entering. It felt like they walked for miles, miles beneath the ground.

Rough stone tunnel went by underfoot, Harry's shoes sometimes dipping into moisture or nearly slipping on a curved surface. After many what was at least several miles and many placid, neutral conversations, the stone tunnel ended.

Professor Quirrell climbed up stone steps, and Harry and the five witches followed after. The seven of them came into a dark, dank stone building. Dirty old stone doors swung open without being touched.

Before them lay marble slabs, rising up from bare ground, upon them names and dates. The tombstones were scattered in nothing like neat rows, and the rest of the graveyard ran wild.

The moon above was over three-quarters full, already seeming bright with night not fully fallen. The Professor came into the center of the scattered graveyard. He stopped walking and waved his wand above his head in a small circle. There was a rumbling sound, and smoothly from the ground rose an altar, at least two meters wide and of black stone carved with grey sigils. And then surrounding the altar groaned up six dark-marble obelisks, regularly spaced, gleaming darkly beneath the fading twilight sky.

"This," said the Quirrell, "is a workspace I made for myself, convenient to either Hogwarts or Hogsmeade." He flourished a hand at the altar. "That is where Miss Granger shall revive, and also where I shall be reborn into my new body. I believe this is what you would call being nice." He looked at Fluttershy in particular.

"You see, the rituals themselves are quite similar; identical in theory and differing only in the execution of a few, relatively minor details of rather small interest. The primary of which being that we shall revive Miss Granger into her original body, whereas I have created a new body in which to transplant my spirit, after which I shall abandon this one.

There is the possibility, perhaps not unlikely, that the ritual will not perform as expected. If that eventuality is to occur, I daresay that you all would benefit from the hand of a wizard experienced in some of the more Eldritch arts that some may call 'dark'. Of course, I do wonder how much of this plan you could reasonably attribute to altruism or 'friendship', for despite these noble intentions, there is a not small part of myself that would wish to practice the ritual upon someone that is not myself."

"Professor, if I may say... I think that's the entire point. Sometimes the best way to advance your own aims is to simultaneously advance those of others. Sometimes, well... sometimes friendship is optimal."

"That's what makes it so magical, darling!" Rarity commented.

"Yes, magical and optimal indeed. On that note, it is time we proceed." The Professor removed the toe ring from among his things and laid it delicately upon the altar.

"Are you familiar, Mr. Potter, with the Ritual of Forbearance?"

Harry shook his head.

"No, I wouldn't imagine so. It's an old ritual, ancient, and passed down among the families of pure blood and great superstition. Its premise is quite similar to that of Muggle cryogenics: the body of a fallen Wizard or Witch is preserved via Transfiguration, which is then sustained not only by the original caster, but the combined magic of friends, families, and acquaintances. To what end they expect, I cannot truly say for certain."

Harry looked up. With the witches behind him, he did not notice that they were suddenly paying rapt attention to the Professor's every word. "Maybe, Professor, they're waiting for something like this."

The Professor shrugged. "Perhaps. It seems to me that the families who indulge in such superstition believe that the exodus will be much more grandiose, a rapture of sorts. Much less... mundane than the operation we are about to perform?"

"Mundane? We're about to resurrect someone from the dead using a stone that literally is the primordial embodiment of an abstract class of Magic. How can you say this is 'mundane'?"

"People tend to have the expectation that great effects are accompanied by similarly dramatic rituals and requirements. The enormity of the implications of this particular task is not quite matched by the execution itself."

"Does... does that magic, the Ritual of Forbearance, ever fail, Mr. Quirrell?" Rainbow Dash asked.

The Professor chuckled at the appellation 'Mister' but answered nonetheless. "Yes, on occasion. There appears to be little rhyme or reason behind such failures, but they are known to occur."

"The stars in the heavens..." Pinkie whispered.

The Professor turned his head and asked sharply, more sharply than he intended, "What did you just say?"

"Oh, my lucky stars!" Pinkie lied. "It sounds a lot like that Horcrux ritual I've heard Harry talk about."

"Oh yes, that one," the Professor laughed darkly. "I trust, Mr. Potter, that you understand its folly?"

Harry nodded. "No continuity of consciousness. It's just a saved state. That, and the fact that a ritual that requires the sacrifice of one life to save another is hardly an optimal recipe to save the entire world."

"You are right on one count, and misguided on another, but no matter. The first iteration of the Horcrux ritual uses the life force of another to power the binding of one's being to an object. A sort of preemptive payment that comes due when the caster's life force returns to a suitable vessel."

"Like a battery for someone's life force..." Harry whispered. "But you mentioned, the 'first iteration'?"

"What you are about to observe is the second iteration," he held the stone up to punctuate his statement.

"Horcrux 2.0..."

"Indeed. With the power of the Philosopher's Stone, no life force is needed to sustain the magic, to bind the spirit to the flesh. What we are about to do is like what the Horcrux ritual is to that of the Ritual of Forbearance."

"What do you mean?"

"Your pink-haired friend is quite observant, the premise of the Ritual of Forbearance is almost identical to that of the Horcrux. In fact, I suspect the latter was derived from, an improvement upon the former. But there is no preemptive payment with the Ritual of Forbearance. No... 'charging of the battery', as you say."

Harry was frowning at this, "But, by that logic, could you not complete the ritual by... You know... Killing someone to replace the person you want to resurrect?"

The Professor grinned wickedly. "Now you're thinking like a proper Dark Wizard. But you think wrong. There are some who say that Magic has a certain wisdom. That to ensure whoever commands it understands its power, it demands a sacrifice. Without the sacrifice, the advance payment of a life for a life, the ritual has no meaning, no value. Indeed, it is precisely because the Ritual of Forbearance is so effortless, requires so little sacrifice, because it is so easy that it is so ubiquitous among Wizarding families, and therefore worthless."

"Do you feel the same way about friendship?" Applejack drawled, somewhat skeptically.

The Professor narrowed his eyes and said nothing for a time. Harry prepared himself for a withering retort that did not come. "Your point is well taken. I confess that I am woefully uneducated as to the value of this 'magic' you call Friendship. I suppose that one could counter my argument by saying, 'Why not?'. That very thought has occurred to me personally, as I confess that I have arranged to have the ritual performed upon myself in the event that my bodily form fails."

Applejack's arms were crossed as if something didn't add up. "Uh-huh."

Anxious to move forward with the resurrection, Harry had subconsciously removed his wand, which the Professor had noticed. "Incidentally, the use of a wand is unnecessary. You learned to sustain a Transfiguration by touch alone, without further use of your wand. You can likewise break your own Transfiguration wandlessly. I, myself, do not have a preference. It seems, however, that you would prefer the faster approach."

Harry nodded and asked, "Are you ready?" to which the Professor returned the nod. He touched the toe-ring with his wand, clearing his mind and whispering the Finite incantation. He turned away as the spell began to become undone, almost like the sped-up reverse of watching something being Transfigured. The toe-ring distorted, flowing together, expanding. Colors changed, textures changed.

Two-thirds of a dead girl lay strewn across the altar, on her side with one arm falling off the altar's edge, the position in which the reversion had chanced to place her. The dead girl was naked, for her clothes were not part of her, and had not been Transfigured.

Out of respect, both Harry and the witches turned away, a gesture that was not lost upon Professor Quirrell. He gestured with his wand, and the naked girl's body lifted into the air, then flared again as dead leaves danced around her and she was clothed in the seeming of a Hogwarts uniform, though the trim was red instead of blue. Hermione Granger's hands folded over her chest, her legs straightened, and her body drifted back down.

The Professor walked forth to the altar once more, orienting the body before him with a wave of his hand to lie straight across the altar. The Dark Lord spoke with high monotone precision, "Flesh, flesh, flesh so wisely hidden."

The obelisks began chanting once more.

Apokatastethi, apokatastethi, apokatastethi to soma hou emoi (emoi).
Apokatastethi, apokatastethi, apokatastethi to soma hou emoi (emoi).

New flesh flowed out of the stumps of the girl's thighs, creeping forward like an ooze and solidifying.

The obelisks ceased chanting. A complete form lay upon the altar, upon which the Professor laid the chunk of red glass, which he allowed to stay there for a time.

Minutes passed.

The chunk of red glass turned, slightly.

Professor Quirrell prodded Hermione Granger's body with his wand. "There is an obstacle," he spoke urgently, with a note of concern that in turn caused Harry more concern than anything else that had occurred that night.

"Obstacle? What obstacle?!" Harry demanded, immediately.

"Her body is restored... the substance is repaired, but not life, or magic. This is the body of a dead Muggle."

"Shocker." Rainbow Dash remarked.

Applejack gave her an elbow to the ribs to quiet her friend. Her previously casual pose had now stiffened, her eyes narrowing slightly as if in anticipation of some threat. The air in the clearing had changed, imperceptibly. The implication was clear; if Harry's friend wasn't getting resurrected, neither was Twilight.

"What, what do you mean the body of a dead Muggle? Are you saying that all the Stone was able to do was just repair her leg?"

The Professor was not listening. He was hurriedly checking her vital signs and otherwise examining her. "Mr. Potter, I think it would be best if you restored the Transfiguration until we can consider this problem further."

"Wait!" Harry blurted, feeling hope return. She needs a spark of life and magic, just a spark to get her started... "I think I have something that might work."

"This," Professor Quirrell spoke softly, "I desire to see."

Harry stood before the reformed body of Hermione Granger on the twilight-lit stone altar and looked at her.

She looks like she is sleeping, not dead. It took a conscious effort to look for breathing, fail to see it and make the deduction. So far as naked perception was concerned... Hermione might as well be alive, right now.
That Hermione Granger would not approve of this situation, taken as a whole, seemed beyond question. But it didn't mean that she would rather stay dead than be alive, other things being equal, though they might not be.

Because you wish to live because my best guess is that you would wish to live...

Harry reached out his shaking left hand and touched Hermione's forehead. It was warm now, not the chill of five degrees Celsius, which meant that Hermione's brain was currently warm and without oxygen, come to think.

That did it, the sense of urgency rising in him.

Harry's feet assumed the stance, his wand swung up to point at Hermione Granger's dead body. The only thing wrong with Hermione's body was that it was dead; everything else about that body was right, only one thing needed changing.

You don't belong here, death.

"Expecto," Harry shouted, feeling the magic and the life rise up into the Patronus Charm that was fueled by both, "PATRONUM!"

The girl in the Hogwarts uniform was surrounded by a blazing aura of silver fire, as the Patronus was born inside her.

Harry staggered, as he felt a dip, a bite. Intuition told Harry that the life and magic that had just flowed into Hermione would never return to him, either one. It hadn't been all his life or all his magic, not by a long shot, there hadn't been time to expend that much, but whatever he'd just expended was gone forever.

And Hermione Granger was breathing, just like she was sleeping, rhythmic inhalations and exhalations. The twilight sky had dimmed further, and Harry could not see if color was returning to her, but it should have been, it certainly should have been. She looked to be sleeping peacefully, and it wasn't because being dead looked like sleeping, it was because she was asleep and her body was fine and nothing was hurting her while she slept.

"Interesting," said the Professor. "Your Patronus draws upon your life as well as your magic... I guessed that much, for it was too powerful for a first-year to fuel with magic alone. And yet there must be more to the puzzle since not just any life-fueled spell would have done... No matter, we must proceed to the next step, the one which our curiously-accented friend suspected that I intended to shirk." He inclined his head towards Applejack.

Another obelisk turned, lay flat upon the ground. "I warn you though, this ritual is Darker than the last. There is an old, lost ritual to sacrifice a magical creature and transfer its magical nature to a subject. The limitations are great; the transfer is temporary, only a few hours, and the subject sometimes dies when the transfer wears off. But the Stone will make it permanent."

"Uh, what do you mean, sacrifice?" Rainbow Dash demanded.

"Stay well back," Quirrell spoke, dismissively. "She comes from a world different than this one, that much I deduced. As do you. If I were to bind her life force to some bodily form on this world using the Stone, I strongly suspect she would be bound to this world permanently, which I assume is not an ideal outcome?"

Rainbow Dash looked down, somewhat abashed. "No."

The Professor nodded at this. "It will seem grim, yes, but your friend's life force will be reborn inside Miss Granger. There are other, much simpler, much more well-known rituals by which one can expel a foreign spirit from one's body. We can deal with that problem when it is time for you to take your leave of this world. Now, I recommend turning around."

The pony-turned-witches nodded, following his logic. Harry, on the other hand, felt like he was free-falling through a tumbling world of new rules that seemed to change at a moment's notice as if he was standing on a massive pile of rugs that kept getting yanked out from under his feet. The Professor removed the violet stone, and an instant later, a unicorn collapsed.

The Professor began a new chant, softer syllables that seemed to seethe through the air like living things; and Harry, feeling a new surge of apprehension, stepped backwards.

Then Harry cried aloud, as pain flared again within his scar. The unicorn crumbled in on itself, becoming ashes hanging in the air, then dust, and then the dust seemed to blow away without going anywhere; it was gone.

He laid the Stone upon Hermione's form once more, clasping her hands around it, and held it there for several minutes. When he was satisfied that the ritual is complete, he looked up.

"She is in there. However, before we wake Miss Granger and your friend, I think it would be prudent to revive my own body. There are a few key enchantments necessary to ensure a, how shall we say, smooth transition, and those enchantments would be much more efficacious with a functioning, healthy body"

"You may want to summon another Patronus, in the event that I, myself, need the same treatment as Miss Granger..." The Professor whispered, and Harry, acknowledging the possibility, dutifully called forth another.

The Professor had moved forward to the altar. He knelt there and seemed to reach deep into the stone of the altar itself, drawing forth a vial of liquid that looked black in the fading twilight. When he spoke again his voice was clipped and precise. "Blood, blood, blood so wisely hidden,"

And the obelisks surrounding the altar began to speak, voices like a chanting chorus coming from the motionless stones, cadences older than Latin, the same chant as before:

Apokatastethi, apokatastethi, apokatastethi to soma mou emoi.
Apokatastethi, apokatastethi, apokatastethi to soma mou emoi.

The obelisks' chant echoed after the end of each line as if they were speaking out of synchrony with each other. The blood was poured from the vial, and it seemed to catch and hang over the altar, slowly expanding through the air, taking on a shape.

Apokatastethi, apokatastethi, apokatastethi to soma mou emoi (emoi).
Apokatastethi, apokatastethi, apokatastethi to soma mou emoi (emoi).

A tall form rested upon the altar, and even in the dimming twilight, it looked too pale.

The Defense Professor placed the Stone upon the tall pale body. It stayed there for a time, minutes at least. The irregular chunk of red glass did not glow, or flash, or give any other indication of power. Then the Stone moved, just a little, turning slightly upon the body.

The Defense Professor took back the Stone into his robes and prodded the tall form that lay motionless upon the altar, touching the eyes with his fingers, poking the chest with his wand.

He placed his hands, both of them, over the body's forehead.

The Dark Lord spoke. "Fal. Tor. Pan."

Suddenly, Harry's scar exploded, a super-nova of hot, white, intense, seemingly infinite pain.

But what was more frightening than that, more frightening than the prospect of an eternity of this, was the fact that the Defense Professors looked scared.

"He... He is here. The Dark Lord, his spirit, it lurks, it waits!" Quirrell's eyes were fully panicked, and the witches looked all around, prepared and ready for a fight, although what they planned to do was a mystery to Harry.

"Professor, what... what do I..." Harry stammered through the pain.

"Harry, RUN!" the Professor wheezed. "The Dark Lord is here, he is free, he is-"

The Professor wavered, ready to collapse. His eyes rolled backwards in his head, and in a voice that Harry could barely hear, Quirinus Quirrell gasped, "Free - oh, free -"

Without any warning, there was a flash like lightning that lit up the entire graveyard, and Harry staggered back a step, his hands involuntarily going to his forehead. The pain, though stinging, had now subsided.

And the too-tall figure sat up upon the altar.

It swung around smoothly, and stood tall upon the ground, at least a head higher than a normal man. The form's limbs were lean and pale, little-muscled but giving an impression of terrible strength.

Harry took another staggering step back, his hands still clasped to his scar. Though the distance between them was wide, Harry felt a sense of terrifying apprehension in the air, as though the sense of doom had always been out of focus and had now clarified, concentrated into a physical pain in the scar on Harry's forehead.

Was that what the Professor's new body was supposed to look like? The nose looked like, it looked like it had malfunctioned during the resurrection process -

The too-tall figure threw back his head and laughed, raising his hands and wand to look at them. The left hand opened wide and it was like a pale half-spider with four over-long legs, fingers caressing the wand held in the other hand. Leaves stirred up from the graveyard, approaching to dance around the too-tall figure, surrounding him and clothing him, reforming into a high-necked shirt and flowing robes; and Lord Voldemort was laughing. Exactly the mirthless laughter that Harry remembered coming from his own throat inside the Dementor's nightmare, precise in tone and timbre.

Red eyes gleamed beneath the fading twilight, their pupils slit like a cat's. The Defense Professor raised himself, quivering, from the ground, and without a second thought, Lord Voldemort pointed his wand and shrieked in a cold, high voice.

"AVADA KEDAVRA!"

So this is the way the world ends, not with a bang - with a whimper.

It should have been glorious. It should have been dramatic. The Defense Professor should have gone out in a blaze of glory, firing curse after curse in a pitched battle in a desperate defense of Harry and his new friends.

It wasn't supposed to end like this. With a pair of words and a flash of green light. With such... ignominy. So... unceremoniously.

But the world didn't work like that. The world was not "just so". If the world paid fair tribute to the lives lost, the husbands and fathers and wives and mothers and daughters and sons and sisters and brothers, the sky would be an infinite black twilight, a monolith to mourn the ever-present specter of rotting, senseless Death.

But the sun comes up. The world still spins. Life goes on.

Because that was the reality of Harry's world. Sometimes good people die for no good reason. Sometimes life ends with nothing more than a blink, with no time to say goodbye, no time to make peace.

Sometimes, the greatest wizard of a generation is obliterated in less than an instant.

In the cold, crystalline rage that had consumed Harry's being, he vaguely noticed that his Patronus was not dimming. In fact, it grew brighter, hotter, more intense with the fires of Harry's emotion. After all, he had been handed a complete roadmap to resurrection.

Step one: preserve the body.

No wait, step one: defeat this blithering fool that calls himself Lord Voldemort, this opportunistic harlequin, this cheap hack, a sad excuse for a 'dark lord' that couldn't even conquer a tiny island of a few thousand without having a spell backfire in his face and terminate his existence for eleven years.

Step two: preserve the body.

Step three: reverse engineer the chanty-obelisk ritual.

Step four: Render it permanent using the Stone.

Step five: Revive him with Patronus.

"And now," the Dark Lord hissed, "I shall complete the task that I set out to do eleven years ago. You, who has been named by prophecy as the one who dares to resist me, you whose parents have escaped my grasp thrice-fold-"

This idiot was monologuing. If Professor Quirrell had been Lord Voldemort, there would have been none of this nonsense, it would have been a quick Avada Kedavra and the whole affair would have been done with.

No, Harry's mind was not on the incompetent moron, floating in front of him, gesticulating with his wand and speaking great volumes about his plans to murder Harry Potter.

No, Harry's mind was with his Patronus, who was currently a world away.

Azkaban
Meanwhile

"I'm not serious."

"I'm not serious."

"I'm not serious."

"I'm not serious."

"I'm not serious."

"I'm not... serious."

"I'm not..."

"I'm not..."

"I'm not... Sirius."

"I'm not Sirius."

"I am not..."

"I am not Sirius Black..."

Peter Pettigrew opened his eyes for the first time in eleven years and saw the world for what it was.

He was not Sirius Black. He was Peter Pettigrew. And he was not supposed to be here.

"I'm... I'm not Sirius Black! I'm Peter Pettigrew. Help me, help!"

He shouted, over and over, until his voice went hoarse. It was a good pain, though, a pain that reminded him that he was alive, truly alive. That there was something he could do, something he wanted to do. It was a strange sensation.

As it so happened, his cries were simultaneously futile and unnecessary, as the human guards of Azkaban were preoccupied with something far more pressing.

Azkaban Command
Meanwhile

"Yes, Bahry, I realize that's what it looks like. That's because THAT'S WHAT'S BLOODY WELL HAPPENING RIGHT NOW." Amelia Bones shrieked into her mirror, causing the Auror Bahry on the other end to hold his copy back a full meter.

Another of Bones' mirrors began chirping amid the cacophony, "This is Calabasas to Command. What the hell is going on?"

Amelia Bones tried to ignore the individual requests, making an emphatic gesture with her hand and activating all of her outbound mirrors at once. "CQ, CQ, CQ. Bravo Oscar November Echo Sierra calling, verification code Sierra Charlie Papa Two Seven Zero One. All guards and Aurors standing by, implement Lazarus Protocol effective immediately. This is not a drill, I repeat, this is not a drill. Implement Lazarus Protocol, effective immediately. I repeat, implement Lazarus Protocol. Secure, contain, protect."

She shut off all the mirrors except for one, as they had simultaneously erupted into a chorus of cries of confusion, fear, warning, anger. She activated the one remaining mirror, through which a crisp, efficient voice answered immediately.

"M-O-M Command, this is Scrimegour standing by. 'Ullo Bones, what's the hap-"

She cut him off before he could even finish his greeting. "Scrimegour, get me Dumbledore, yesterday. The dementors are fleeing Azkaban!"

"Oh, bloody hell." Rufus Scrimegour muttered as he connected the two mirrors without flinching.

Hogwarts, the Headmaster's Office
Meanwhile

In Albus Dumbledore's empty office, a mirror crackled and a voice began desperately shrieking through into the empty space, receiving no response except for echoing silence.

Between Hogsmeade and Hogwarts
Meanwhile

The entirety of the Dementor corps of Azkaban had dutifully followed the rage-fuelled Patronus, who threatened (with full intention of seeing the threat through) and commanded them to abandon their post. The Patronus hurtled through the air at a speed an order of magnitude faster than even the most advanced of muggle jets. The Dementors had no trouble keeping up, for they were not truly physical beings. The Patronus expected, demanded that they follow, and so they did.

The night sky darkened behind the gloating Voldemort, who was spending a great deal of time describing his own power and plans for domination, before moving on to meticulously enumerating the various weaknesses of the young Harry James Potter-Evans-Verres.

It was not that Harry didn't hear what Lord Voldemort was saying. He found that he simply did not care. When the Dark Lord commanded Harry to respond, to speak for himself and answer the challenge, Harry did not reply. There were no words, no rejoinders, nothing but the all-consuming expectation of Death, an expectation which was about to swiftly be realized.

Voldemort looked upward as he sensed the Dementors' presence, a massive cloud following the pinprick of blinding light. He cackled gratuitously, gesturing above. "You intend to end me, truly? You intend to destroy my immortal soul with these creatures you seem to command?'

Once again, Harry had no response for Lord Voldemort. He spoke simply one word, through his Patronus, to the gathered darkness that hovered in the sky above.

"FEED."

Lord Voldemort closed his eyes with a smile, and shuddered. "Thank you, boy," he spoke with crisp, efficient diction as he began walking towards Harry.

Harry stiffened, slightly. Voldemort's body language and mannerisms had changed in an instant. No longer was he gesticulating wildly and engaging in overdramatic, unnecessary monologues. He moved with a swift sense of purpose, a confidence that flew in the face of the fact that over a hundred specters of Death floated above, ready to feast upon his immortal soul and put a permanent end to his very brief rise to power.

This was not the comic-book villain from moments earlier. This was something altogether different. Something frightening. Something that reminded him, inexplicably, of...

No.

"Do you remember, boy?" He spoke as he moved closer, his wand still at his side, "When I told you that ssssnakess can't lie?"

What was this?

"Or perhaps, when I implored you that 'there are gatessss you do not open, there are ssssealsss you do not breach'?"

No.

"Yes, boy. You tried to end my true life jusst then, sstupid child. Now cursse iss lifted, and I may kill you any time I wissh."

Curse? What. Is. This?

"Behold, for I am Quirinusss Quirrell, your mentor, your friend, your teacher, your preccciousss Defenssse Professssor."

Tom Riddle.

The words seemed to echo inside Harry's head, sparking resonances that as quickly died away, broken patterns trying to complete themselves and failing.

Tom Riddle is a

Tom Riddle was the

Riddle

No.

Harry desperately tried to shove aside the only conclusion he could come to. He discarded all of his training as a rationalist and prayed for something other than the truth to be true. He would live a lifetime in shameful ignorance and darkness if only this weren't the truth.

He hasn't told you anything that is 100% confirmation. Maybe, what if - Yes, that's it. Lord Voldemort, upon taking over the intended body of the man I knew as the Defense Professor, was also able to assume his memories. And now he's using those to mess with me. To convince me that... To convince me...

No.

A voice in Harry's head would not allow this harlequinade to persist. That same voice asked, demanded, to what end? Why? Why a deception, instead of the truth? And Harry found he had no good answers.

Occam's Razor slashed mercilessly through the desperate webs of narrative that Harry tried to spin, the lifelines he tried to hold on to in order to prevent himself from being dragged down by the inexorable conclusions that he just...

knew...

was...

true.

The full weight of the realization dawned on him, the sickening magnitude of the betrayal and the colossal depths of his own stupidity and blindness and wishful thinking and irrationality and mistakes. He had seen and ignored a thousand red flags and failed to see a thousand more. He had handed Lord Voldemort one of the most powerful artifacts in existence on a silver platter, and aided in the banishment of the only Wizard possibly capable of defeating him.

Harry had ushered in an era of darkness, and it was entirely his fault.

His fault.

At this, the blinding light of his Patronus flickered and blinked out of existence, leaving him naked to the wraiths above who now conformed to the expectations and commands of their new master, Quirinius Quirrell, David Monroe, Jeremy Jaffe, Tom Marvolo Riddle, he who went by a thousand names: the Dark Lord Voldemort.

Chapter 17: Everybody Wants to Rule the World

Sydney, Australia

The Dark Mark on Lucius Malfoy's arm was hot-white with pain, and both his and Draco's minds here spinning, albeit in different directions. Draco pulled at the hem of his aunt's dress. "Aunt Bella... Mum... you heard him. You heard what he said, what was at stake."

Narcissa Malfoy was shaking her head desperately, "No. No, Lucius, please, don't go. I can't lose you again. I just can't. And Draco, too, oh Draco. He's so young, my baby..."

"My love, to ignore the call would be death, not just for me, but for all of you. Dumbledore is gone, there is nothing now to stand in the Dark Lord's way. My absence would not go unnoticed. But Draco, you... You cannot. You must not."

"Dad! You heard what Dumbledore said! 'The unlikely friend of the one marked by lightning?' And 'the gate thrown open by the one who is bound by the Dark Lord?' This isn't a coincidence and we can't just ignore it."

Bellatrix Black was nodding, sadly, as she removed the irregular, orange chunk of glass from her dress. "Wheels are in motion, Lucius. Wheels that rotate far above our heads. You are a Malfoy, you are cunning and wise, you can navigate the waters ahead. But this must be done."

She thrust the gem into Draco's hand which closed around it. He could feel some ineffable sense of power that was locked behind the sparkling facets of the gem's face, but he had no sense of what that power might mean or how to use it.

Lucius sighed. "Narcissa, I love you. I never stopped loving you these twelve long years. If I don't return-"

"Don't say that. Don't. Just don't. Just... return. Stay alive, my love. And you," she turned to Draco, "Keep your head down, don't act until you're absolutely sure of what must be done. Make me proud, son."

She planted a kiss on Draco's forehead, then another on Lucius' cheek, and watched with deep concern as father and son disapparated with a dull POP.

The Graveyard
Moments Before

Pinkie Pie's arms were outstretched, examining her sparkling nail polish, seemingly oblivious to the gossamer, shimmering dagger hovered in midair at her throat. "I tollllllld you!" she called out in a sing-song voice.

"Should have seen this one coming from a mile away," grumbled Applejack.

"I don't understand what is happening," Harry said. There was nothing else left. "Please explain to me."

The Dark Lord was now regarding Harry with a grim look. "Your intellect is not everything I hoped for, but it should suffice for this, Tom. Now answer me, why am I calling you Tom?"

Harry's mouth seemed to know the answer before his brain could manage to focus on the question. "Tom Riddle is your name. Our name. That's who Lord Voldemort is, or was, or - something."

Professor Quirrell nodded. "Better. You have already vanquished the Dark Lord, the one and only time that you will ever do so. I have already destroyed all but a remnant of Harry Potter, eliminating the difference between our spirits and enabling us to reside in the same world."

The Dark Lord was now regarding Harry with a grim look. "When girl-child died, wass in company of sschool'ss Sseer, heard prophecy sspoken that you would become force of vasst desstruction. You would become threat beyond imagination, beyond apocalypsse. That iss why I went to ssuch lengthss to undo my killing of girl-child, keep it undone."

"Are," what "are you sure," what.

"Dare not ssay sspecificss to you. Prophecy I heard of mysself led me to fulfill it. Have not forgotten that dissasster." Voldemort backed further away from Harry, red slitted eyes fixed upon the Boy-Who-Lived, gun unwavering in the left hand. "All thiss, all I have done, iss to ssmassh that desstiny at every point of intervention. If ssome fate makess me fail in what comess next, idiot-child of foretold desstruction, then you musst kill yoursself to ssave girl-child. Elsse all you claim to value diess by your own hand."

"Sir," Harry's voice went up an octave, "Sir," another octave, "I... listen, we both heard Dumbledore's warning, and we both know that he wasn't speaking to me. He spoke of 'tearing apart the stars in heaven', which isn't necessarily a bad thing."

"Ssilence, fool. Remain ssilent unlesss given leave by me to sspeak. Keep your wand pointed down and do not raisse it unlesss told. Elsse you die upon the sspot, and mark that I ssaid that in Parsseltongue."Voldemort reached into the altar again. "You are letting your foolish wishful thinking cloud your judgment, blinding you to the obvious conclusion you should have drawn ages ago. Dumbledore's warning was nothing more than confirmation that the path I have laid out for us is the correct one to guide us through the coming storm."

For a second Harry's mind couldn't process what he was seeing, and then he saw that Voldemort was holding a human arm, severed near the shoulder; it seemed too thin, that arm.

The Dark Lord pressed his wand to the flesh above the severed arm's elbow, and the fingers twitched, twitched like they were alive; by dim moonlight, Harry saw a darker mark appear on that flesh, just above the elbow.

Seconds later the first hooded figure appeared inside the graveyard with the popping sound of an Apparition. A moment after that came another pop, and then another.

The hooded figures wore silver skull masks, and moonlight fled from the robes beneath them.

"Master!" cried one of the black robes, the third to arrive. The voice was of peculiar timbre, from behind the silver skull mask. "Master - it has been so long - we had lost hope -"

"Silence!" shouted the high voice of the Dark Lord Voldemort. Every trace of Professor Quirrell was now gone from the too-tall figure. "Train your wand upon the Boy-Who-Lived, and watch him! Do not be distracted, not by anything! Stun him at once if he moves, if he begins to speak!"

More pops. Between graves, behind a tree, in all the shadowy spaces, more black robes were Apparating, all hooded and masked. Some of them voiced exclamations of joy, many of those sounding rather forced; others moved forwards as though to greet their Master. Voldemort gave them all the same instruction, except that some were commanded to Cruciate Harry Potter if he moved, others to restrain the Boy-Who-Lived if he moved, others told to fire hexes and curses, others told to cancel his magic.

Thirty-eight pops, Harry counted before the black robes and skull masks seemed to stop arriving. All of them were now holding their wands pointed at Harry, aligned in a semicircle before him, where they wouldn't get into each other's lines of fire.

Behind one of the masked, robed Death Eaters was a smaller figure, bathed in shadow, but it unmistakably was...

"Draco?!" Harry wheezed. Draco did not reply.

The Dark Lord surveyed the gathered masses with grim satisfaction. The gibbous moon riding higher in the cloudless sky, the stars and wash of the Milky Way visible in all their majesty within the darkness.

"Welcome, my Death Eaters," spoke Lord Voldemort's voice, smooth and high and terrible. "No, do not look at me, you fools! Eyes upon the Potter child! Ten years, it has been, ten years since we last met. Yet you answer my call as though it were yesterday..." The Dark Lord Voldemort came near to one hooded figure, tapped fingers upon the mask. "In a hastily Transfigured mockery of a Death Eater's true armor, with a childish Charm to distort your voice. Explain, Mr. White."

"Master," one of the robes said in a faltering voice distorted by his skull mask. "Master, please - I would never defy you, I am obedient as you see - but Master, I beg you, let me return, the better to serve you later - I came here in haste, forsaking - Master, with so many of us being gone, others will wonder, they will mark the absences, who has disappeared. Soon there shall be no alibi I can offer."

A cold high laugh. "Ah, Mr. White, the most delinquent of my servants. I have less need of you than I once did, Mr. White. In two days' time, the Death Eaters shall walk openly. My powers have increased, and I have just this day disposed of Dumbledore." More gasps of shock arose from the Death Eaters, Voldemort paid them no heed. "Tomorrow I shall slay Bones, Crouch, Moody, and Scrimgeour, if they have not fled. The rest of you shall go into the Ministry and the Wizengamot, and cast Imperius Curses as I direct you. We are finished waiting. By tomorrow's nightfall, I shall have declared myself Lord Ruler of Britain!"

Voldemort resumed pacing behind the black-robed figures. "I suppose you are also wondering what Harry Potter is doing here... Why he is a guest at my rebirthing party."

"I know, Master!" said one of the robes. "You mean to prove your power by killing him, in front of us all, to leave no doubt as to which of you is stronger! To show how your Killing Curse can slay even this so-called Boy-Who-Lived!"

There was a pause. None of the cloaked figures dared to speak.

Slowly, the Dark Lord Voldemort, in his high-collared shirt and dark robes, turned to face the Death Eater who had spoken.

"That," whispered Voldemort in a voice chill as death, "is a little too much folly for me to credit, Mr. Sallow. You heard that theory of how I died, and tried to provoke me into repeating a mistake?" Lord Voldemort was floating, rising high off the ground. "I suppose you came to prefer your laziness to my mastery, Macnair? "

With a sudden movement, Lucius Malfoy drew out his wand and cried "Avada Kedavra! ". Both he and the Death Eater who'd spoken was suddenly surrounded by a blue haze. Voldemort simply tilted to one side in midair, dodging the green bolt. His hand that didn't hold a wand was making other gestures, further colors and layers building up in his shielding haze with each gesture completed. Lucius shouted to the gathered wizards, "This cannot be the true Dark Lord, why would he keep the Potter boy alive?! This is a trick of some sort! Help me, my brothers!"

Other Death eaters shifted uncomfortably, seeing the merit of Lucius' accusation, but too terrified to do anything about it. Their indecision, however, crystallized into inaction as Macnair suddenly fell in seven flaming pieces to the ground, chunks of flesh with the cauterized edges still glowing. A quick flick of Voldemort's wand and Lucius Malfoy was frozen on the spot, lifted into the air, as Draco gasped, "No!"

"Eyes and wands on Harry Potter, all of you," Voldemort repeated, his voice low and dangerous. "I command your Marks, as I always shall. I am immortal. Macnair acted in sheer stupidity, with rank opportunism just then, and so to him, I delivered punishment. But you, Lucius... you showed bravery, cunning. Perhaps you truly did believe me to be an imposter, a pretender, a mere trick concocted by the Potter boy designed to lure you here to your deaths."

With another lazy flick of Voldemort's wand and a whispered word, Lucius began convulsing, and the Dark Lord continued. "No matter. When I flay his mind apart, I shall know for certain. Either way, to Lucius, I deliver mercy. Crucio!" he hissed, with louder venom.

Draco was openly weeping. The Dark Lord knew, of course, that Lucius did not truly believe him to be an impostor. But better to keep him alive so as to maintain leverage over Draco and therefore leverage over Harry Potter. He continued to whip his wand, torturing Lucius with the Cruciatus curse.

The only sounds that pierced the night were the shrieks of Voldemort's curse and the screams of Lucius' pain. But soon, a new sound would join them, that of gasps of shock and mutters of confusion.

At first, the pain that suddenly shot into the arms of the gathered Death Eaters was thought to be the Dark Lord's rage. But those who had felt his punishment knew immediately that this was a different kind of pain, the hot, purifying pain of a wound stitching itself together.

It was the pain of healing.

Without warning, their masks began melting away. Many of the Death Eaters' eyes were momentarily drawn down to their now blank wrists and naked faces; their Dark Marks were gone. But their attention, along with that of Voldemort, Harry, and the five witches who stood with knives at their throats, was quickly drawn to a new site: a towering pillar of flame that erupted in the middle of the graveyard, behind the half-circle of Death Eaters.

When the tower had reached its full height, the menacing figure of Albus Dumbledore emerged, his wand leveled at Lord Voldemort.

His deep green eyes, the shade of dragon-emeralds, flashed with unbound rage.

"It was foolish of you to come here tonight, Tom."

Chapter 19: Spike, the Brave and Glorious

" 'The Limit of One Over X as X Approaches Zero Sack'. So... the Infin-"

A giant foam finger instantiated over Spike's lips, forcibly preventing him from speaking, as Discord looked around conspiratorially.

"Shhh. We don't want to be using the I-Word. Or the A-Word or the M-Acronym. And we certainly don't want to draw any parallels between our protagonist and the T-word. The Mouse, he's always listening."

"Who?"

"Never you mind. Listen, for this next step, we're going to need to give you a little makeover," at this, Discord produced a measuring tape and an oversized pair of scissors and began to snip at imaginary spots in the air. As he did so, a flickering form began to build itself up around Spike. It started as a purple robe, fringed with black, and built itself up until it became man-shaped.

"What are you doing?" Spike asked, in a voice that was suddenly aged, gravelly and wizened.

"Hush, I'm concentrating." Discord instantiated a photograph and a pen and began sketching a face in midair above the neckline of the robes that had built up around Spike, looking to the photograph for reference.

As Spike moved his paws, the arms of the simulacrum that had built up around him moved as well. Discord nodded in approval and clapped his paw and claw together to finalize the illusion. Spike worked his jaw up and down and tested out his new voice.

"I am old and wise. You must listen to me because I am old." Spike let out an awkward laugh as he lifted his arms up and down, oblivious to the fact that Madam Pomfrey, the hospital matron, had just walked in through the entryway.

"Professor Dumbledore, Madame Maxime... What are you- I mean, hello, good evening to you. Did you need something?"

Spike put his arms down quickly, and Discord, who had seamlessly transitioned himself into the form of Madame Maxime, replied in a flawless, if not over-the-top French accent, "Ah, yes, but zee 'Eadmaster was just about to show me zee trinkets in 'is office. Weren't you now, Dumbly-dore?"

"Um... Yes. Yes I was," Spike spoke in the voice of Albus Dumbledore. "Let's, um, let's go."

Poppy Pomfrey narrowed her eyes skeptically for a moment, but then they widened in shock as she came to an embarrassing realization. Poppy had always assumed that Dumbledore was just a touch mancy, what with the way he always carried on with the young boys. But here she was, interrupting a soon-to-be tryst. She wasn't exactly sure how old the Headmaster was, but he was certain to be at least a few decades older than Madame Maxime.

Good for him, he deserves it, what with all the work he does around here... even if she is a bit long through the bone... Madame Pomfrey thought to herself.

"You two have fun!" she intoned out loud, waving in a stilted fashion with an awkward smile on her face.

"Oh yes, we will 'ave oodles of it!" Discord-Maxime tittered, giving Madame Pomfrey an exaggerated wink. "You know what zey say about zee wizards with large wands?"

Madame Pomfrey blinked a few times. "No...? What do they say?"

Discord-Maxime rolled her eyes as they left the hospital wing.

"Look at him, he's just like Philomena!" Spike was scratching the Phoenix in Dumbledore's office underneath its beak. At first, it eyed him skeptically but upon sensing his good, if not different nature than his true master, he quickly warmed up. "But what exactly are we waiting for?"

Discord hummed a little tune and drummed his paw on the desk. "Oh, you'll know it when you see it. Or, feel it."

Fawkes suddenly began to retch, as if he were a cat coughing up a hairball.

"No, no, little guy, it's alright!"

But despite Spike's reassurances, Fawkes opened its mouth wide and vomited forth a stream of liquid Phoenix-fire all over the false Dumbledore. He coughed up a few more times and then belched out a pair of objects: a long, dark-grey wand and a short rod of dark stone, which promptly arced through the air towards Spike's not-face, passing through the spectral form and clattering to the floor of the office.

"That," Discord cackled, "is what we were waiting for. Now, remember, the second Mirror is hidden inside the first Mirror, which normally shows you your deepest desire, which should be the second Mirror because the only way for you to rescue Rarity is by retrieving the second Mirror from inside the first Mirror, but the first Mirror will only show the second Mirror to someone who knows the second Mirror is there but no one alive knows the second Mirror is inside the first Mirror, except now for you. You got it?"

"I... I don't know?"

"Third base!"

"What?"

"Third... Oh, come on! I'm getting tired of no one understanding my little references."

"Uh, okay? So... I go down to the third-floor corridor, sing a little song to the three-headed dog, then follow the rooms until I reach the Mirror. The first Mirror. Right?"

"Yep." Discord pouted, moodily.

"And this rod here will transform the Mirrors into their true form..."

"Yep."

"And you promise I get to eat them when all is said and done?"

"Naturally."

"And then how will I find my way to Rarity?"

"Oh, I'm sure some ridiculous trope will apply. Just follow your heart or something like that. Or maybe a good Deus Ex Machina will fly out of the air like a Phoenix that can teleport people to arbitrary locations."

"Are you serious?"

"You know, I really have to restrain myself from making that 'Peter Pettigrew' joke for the third time."

Spike rolled Dumbledore's eyes and grabbed the wand and rod off the ground with his mouth, which also served as Dumbledore's right hand.

"So, how exactly do you know so much about all of this?" Spike asked, suddenly curious.

"The truth is, I cheated a bit. I read the plot summary on Discordpedia."

"You what?"

Discord produced his copy of Discordpedia and began leafing through the pages, "Here, let's see... The Moon's Apprentice... Friendship is Optimal... All American Girl... Ah, yes, here we are. The Longest Day. See, right here. Chapter 21: 'Spike, the Brave and Glorious'."

Discord began to read from the entry, " 'Spike, disguised as Albus Dumbledore (courtesy of Discord), travels to the Headmaster's office to retrieve the Elder Wand and the Line of Merlin, an artifact that was brought to Earth by none other than Princess Celestia-"

"Princess Celestial was here?!" Spike interrupted.

"Patience, patience, little dear. Ahem, as I was saying. '...by none other than Princess Celestia, the true identity of the wizard known on Earth-616 as Merlin, as a tool to strip away the vessels that contain the various Elements of Harmony. Spike travels to the third-floor corridor and removes the Mirror of Erised from inside the Mirror of Noitilov, and then uses the Line of Merlin to extract the Space and Time Stones, respectively. Fawkes then appears, and in a burst of Phoenix-fire, transports them both to the graveyard where Harry and the ponies are currently being held hostage by Lord Voldemort.' See? Clear as crystal."

"What even is this thing? I have a whole chapter named after me? What else does it say about me? Gimme, gimme!" Spike's hands shot outward to try to grab the book, but the illusory hands of Albus Dumbledore passed through the illusory form of Discord and his book.

"Get away, this is my private diary! You don't want to upset me, I might just change the ending so that Harry just does something crazy like snapping his fingers and wiping out half the universe."

Spike took a step back, "Could... could you actually do something like that?"

"Oh, silly dragon, I can do whatever I want! Or at least, I can say that I can."

Spike paced back and forth, nervously. "Ok, well this is starting to make my head hurt. So just to make totally certain, once I show up, this wand will do all the fighting for me? And then that will make sure Rarity is safe?"

Discord shrugged. "That's what the book says!"

And at that, with a deep breath, Spike prepared himself for the next steps he needed to take.

Chapter 20: Ragnarok

Lord Voldemort surveyed the battlefield, looking out over the fallen bodies of both loyal and former Death Eaters, briefly scanning past the still-moaning, amputated body of Macnair and the headless corpse of Lucius Malfoy, across the sleeping form of Hermione and the wandless Harry and Draco, before finally settling on the remaining captives arranged before him.

All in all, his plan was still progressing nicely. The boy was here, the girl revived, the Stone was his, and a convenient vessel for the Unbreakable Vow had shown up. As for the girls, he would simply kill the spares when the time came.

"Tell me, Draco, This is not a trick, and you will answer truthfully or bear the consequences. If the boy freely chose to swear to you an oath, even knowing your father for a former Death Eater, you would trust in his words? Answer me!" Voldemort's voice rose to a shriek.

"I... yes. I would."

"Good," Voldemort said coldly. "The potential for trust must exist to be sacrificed. And for the bonder of the Unbreakable Vow... which of you shall sacrifice their magic? It shall be quite the long Vow... much longer than usual... much magic shall be required for that..." Voldemort smiled his awful smile as he observed the five witches standing before him, before settling on the pale-skinned, violet-haired witch who was protectively holding the dog-that-wasn't-Dumbledore. "You. You seem rather generous. What is your name, your true name?"

"Rarity Belle," she spat defiantly.

"Wait a minute, your surname is 'Belle'? So your sister's name is..." Rainbow Dash couldn't resist the question.

"Yes, dear. 'Sweetie Belle Belle'." Rarity interrupted.

Applejack and Rainbow Dash both stifled a giggle, prompting the Dark Lord to shriek, "ENOUGH! Put the dog down."

Rarity did as he commanded, and another (albeit smaller) knife instantiated at his throat as well.

The Dark Lord went on pacing in front of his captives. "Today - though I hardly expect even you to believe me - today we are doing Merlin's work, children. Before me stands a great danger, who in his blundering folly has been prophesied to wreak destruction such as even I can scarcely imagine. The Boy-Who-Lived! The boy who frightens Dementors!"

Voldemort laughed, a strange bitter laugh. When he spoke on his high voice was precise. "Here is the oath's intent, Draco Malfoy, Rarity Belle, Harry Potter. Listen well and comprehend the Vow that must be sworn, for its intent is also binding, and you three must share an understanding of its meaning. You will swear, Harry Potter, not to destroy the world, to take no risks when it comes to not destroying the world. This Vow may not force you into any positive action, on account of that, this Vow does not force your hand to any stupidity. Do you understand that, Draco, Rarity? We are dealing with a prophecy of destruction. A prophecy! They can fulfill themselves in twisted ways. I must be cautious that this Vow itself does not bring that prophecy about. I dare not let this Vow force Harry Potter to stand idly after some disaster is already set in motion by his hand, because he must take some lesser risk if he tries to stop it. Nor must the Vow force him to choose a risk of truly vast destruction, over a certainty of lesser destruction. But all Harry Potter's foolishness," Voldemort's voice climbed, "all his recklessness, all his grandiose schemes, and good intentions - he shall not risk them leading to disaster! He shall not gamble with the Earth's fate! No researches that might lead to catastrophe! No unbinding of seals, no opening of gates!" Voldemort's voice lowered again. "Unless this very Vow itself is somehow leading into the destruction of the world, in which case, Harry Potter, you must ignore it in that particular regard. You will not trust yourself alone in making such a determination, you must confide honestly and fully in your trusted friend, and see if that one agrees. Such is this Vow's meaning and intent. It forces only such acts as you might choose yourself, having learned that he is a prophesied instrument of destruction. For the capacity for choice must also exist, to be sacrificed. Do you understand, Rarity?"

Rarity nodded weakly while Spike growled impotently, "I - I think so. But I too agree that I really don't think Harry would do-"

"Silence, fool. And you, Draco?"

"I think, that it must be repeated to me."

Voldemort smiled that too-wide smile and said it all again using different words.

"And now," Voldemort said coldly, "Harry Potter and Draco Malfoy, I will return your wands to you, and you will keep your wands low, and touch your wand together-"

"Just the tips?" Rainbow Dash giggled.

"Yes, just the-" Voldemort's anger suddenly surged as he realized that the rainbow-haired witch in front of him was joking at a time like this. He bade the Dementors to fly lower, in a wordless attempt to stifle any further interruptions.

"You know that she can kill those things, don't ya, Mister Quirrell?" Applejack asked with her arms folded.

"What, those Demendroids? I sure can, wanna see?" Rainbow Dash squinted upwards to try to see them amid the darkness of the night sky and the canopy of trees above.

"Yes, I would like to see," Fluttershy whispered.

Pinkie was too busy examining the sparkly gems embedded in Spike's collar to comment.

In response, the knives that were hovering an inch from their throats drew close against their flesh, and Voldemort shouted, "Another word and the four of you will be slain on the spot." He directed his attention back towards Harry, Draco, and Rarity. "You will speak such words as I direct you. If you speak any other word, then I will cut you down, and the rest of you as well. Do you understand?"

The three nodded. Harry was chilled, and shivering, and not only because he was naked in the night. He didn't understand why Voldemort was not just killing him. There seemed to be only a single line leading into the future, and it was Voldemort's chosen line, and Harry did not know what came after this.

"Rarity Belle," said Voldemort. "Touch your hand to Harry Potter's hand, and repeat these words. Magic that flows in me, bind this Vow."

Rarity spoke those words. Behind Voldemort the obelisks chanted, a language that Harry did not know; three times they repeated their words, then fell silent.

"Draco Malfoy," said Voldemort. "Think of the reasons why you might trust this boy if he had given this oath freely. Think of that potential for trust, and sacrifice it as you say..."

"By my trust that I hold for you," said Draco, "be you held."

And then it was Harry Potter's turn to repeat Lord Voldemort's words, and Harry did so.

"I vow..." Harry said. His voice shook, but he spoke. "That I shall not... by any act of mine... destroy the world... I shall take no chances... in not destroying the world... if my hand is forced... I may take the course... of lesser destruction over greater destruction... unless it seems to me that this Vow itself... leads to the world's end... and the friend... in whom I have confided honestly... agrees that this is so. By my own free will..." Harry could feel it, as the rite was invoked, the shining cords of power wrapping around his wand and Draco's wand, wrapping around his hand where Rarity's hand touched it, wrapping around his self on some disturbingly abstract level. Harry could feel himself invoking his power of free choice, and he knew that his next words would sacrifice it, that this was absolutely the last chance to turn back.

"...so shall it be," said the coldly precise voice of Lord Voldemort.

"...so shall it be," Harry repeated, and he knew at that moment that the content of the Vow was no longer something he could decide whether or not to do, it was simply the way in which his body and mind would move. It was not a vow he could break even by sacrificing his life in the process. Like water flowing downhill or a calculator summing numbers, it was just a thing-Harry-Potter-would-do.

"Did the Vow take, Draco?"

Draco sounded like he was weeping. "Yes... I have lost so much, please..."

"Return to your places... Good," said Voldemort. The Dark Lord floated high in the air, the black-clad figure overlooking the graveyard. The Dementors swarmed at his behest, surrounding the group, preparing to feast if the next step did not go as planned. "Better. Now I shall kill the Boy-Who-Lived."

Beneath the moonlight glints a tiny fragment of silver, a fraction of a line...

Voldemort noticed the trick of light from the corner of his eye and immediately reacted, sparing no time for further dramatics. As he loosed his mental instructions out for the Dementors to follow, the line expanded into something larger, something brighter, something blinding. The Dementors swooped downward.

(black robes, falling)

With a quick flick of his wrist, the knives that were poised threateningly against Spike, Pinkie Pie, Applejack, Rainbow Dash, Fluttershy, and Rarity pushed into their flesh and drew themselves savagely across their throats.

...blood spills out in liters

The five witches and the dog fell to the ground in crumpled heaps, and Harry barely had time to register the shock before the blinding silver light was the only thing that he or anyone in the graveyard could see.

...and someone screams a word.

Chapter 22: Friendship is Magic

"Ah, this is much better." Discord sighed, "Don't you agree?"

Hermione looked around the library, which seemed imperceptibly different than it had a moment before: simultaneously less concrete but somehow more real. Notably, Twilight was missing.

"Where did Twilight go?"

"Just give it a bit, she'll be here any second. We need to catch up with what's happening." Discord twiddled his 'thumbs' for a moment and whistled a little ditty, and after a few moments, Twilight dutifully winked back into existence.

She shook her mane a bit, taking a few moments to reorient herself. Twilight was suspicious, as she always was whenever Discord was in one of his moods like he appeared to be in now.

"What did you do? Why does it feel different?" Twilight demanded.

"Acknowledging my limitations, that's all, my little pony. I would say I'm playing to my strengths, but that would imply that writing is my strong suit. Which, let's be honest, I have a bad habit of taking twenty-thousand words to get the action going, and my publishing schedule has been more than a little erratic." Discord floated lazily across the void as he spoke.

"I have no idea what you're talking about. What's really going on here?" Twilight was pacing underneath where Discord floated.

"No, you wouldn't, would you? But you, on the other hand, my bookish friend... You understand, don't you?" He flew up close to Hermione and sat down, propping himself up with a claw, and began combing her coat with a comb that was gripped in his wing.

"I... This whole thing. At first, I thought this was a figment of my imagination. That I was dead, and that this was just a dream, that my brain's pattern still 'existed' in some abstract sense... But then she showed up, and you showed up. And it's not that, is it? This isn't my imagination, this is Imagination.

"Harry would always go on about cryogenics, about how it was logical and rational and how you'd have to be an idiot not to hand over a lot of money based on some seriously questionable science. We didn't quite see eye to eye on the issue, but his heart was in the right place. And I'm pretty certain that Harry would have preserved my body..." she shuddered for a moment as she considered this, "...or at least my head, when I... you know. When I died."

"Do go on, this exposition is enthralling."

"You don't seem very enthralled, Discord." Twilight pointed out.

"Yes, well she's taking quite a long time to get to the good stuff, isn't she?"

Hermione huffed a bit, "Well, excuse me, but it's not every day that someone is thrust into an afterlife with no explanation and has to figure everything out herself!""

Discord threw his arms up in mock defensiveness, "Speak for yourself! Anyway, do go on."

"Well. Well, then Twilight Sparkle showed up and told me about this whole other world that existed, and the whole thing just felt like... A story. A cartoon, a TV show, a book. This couldn't have just been my imagination. And if Harry had preserved my body using Magic, it's entirely possible, probable even, that other people had been preserved using the same means. Harry, despite how clever he thinks he is, isn't the only person with lofty ideals and ideas.

"So, as far as I can tell, this place is a construct of Magic, a place of pure imagination, of all form and no substance. And look, despite the fact that Harry can be a bit silly at times, he's my friend, and I'm his friend. He's a good person, and he wouldn't want me to stay dead, to stay in this place. And you..." She turned to Twilight, "I think your friends probably feel the same way."

Twilight nodded, "I came to your world because I was following a prophecy. Ever since my world was created, our worlds have been bound together, and the time has come for that bond to end. In a way, at least to you, our world will be destroyed. And yet, in another way, it will still live on forever, in memory. But your world, something else must happen entirely. And that's what I wasn't clear on." Twilight cleared her throat as she remembered the relevant part of the prophecy, " 'The world that birthed this world must be destroyed, for this is the only way to save that world.' I didn't understand it, how could destroying the world save the world? So I came here to investigate..."

Discord cackled, "And your investigation was cut short in quite a spectacular manner. Dismembered and devoured by a dark wizard doing dark deeds!" He preened for a moment. "I have quite the talent for alliteration, don't I?"

"Sure, Discord." Twilight continued, "I told my friends that if I didn't come back, they needed to follow in my footsteps, not for my sake, but for the sake of this world. Maybe for the sake of all worlds, too."

"Twilight," Hermione asked, putting her hoof to her chin, "Do you remember the full text of the prophecy?"

She nodded. "It's actually a continuation of a prophecy that I thought we had already solved. It's honestly the longest prophecy I've ever seen. It starts like this...

'On the longest day of the thousandth year, the stars will aid in her escape, and she will bring about nighttime eternal.

For the stars in the heavens have grown heavy, an anchor that if left unchecked will destroy the world from which Equus was born.

Following the ninth season of strife, the world that birthed this world must be destroyed, for this is the only way to save that world.

The stars shall be torn from the heavens, and in that sunless sky, a new eternal day shall dawn for Equus.

The elements, the stones of infinite power must be sought, understood, and embraced: strange charms of truth and beauty which make up become down.

The ones who command the six forces must stand before the world, who will bear witness to its power and speak together:

'You are here. The one who shall tear apart the very stars in heaven. You are here. You are the end of the world.' "

Hermione frowned, hard. "Strange, charm, truth, beauty, up, down... Those are the names of the six quarks."

Discord giggled and clapped his hands with glee, but said nothing.

Twilight cocked her head, "The six... quarks? That's kind of a silly name, isn't it? What are they?"

"They're... Well, they're the building blocks of everything. Life, matter, even reality, really. Without them, there would be nothing."

"That sounds a lot like the Elements of Harmony."

"And you said... 'The ones who command the six forces'. That doesn't seem... There's something about that. 'The ones'. Not one person, but many. A group of people. Maybe even an entire world of people?"

Twilight nodded in agreement, "At first, I thought it might have referred to my friends because, in our world, we can harness the power of the Elements of Harmony."

"But that doesn't really fit, does it? You don't really... command the Elements. You harness them, you use them, but they don't really do what you ask, do they?"

Twilight shook her head, "No, they don't. It's almost like they have a mind of their own. A certain... wisdom, you might say."

"Yes... I think, I think perhaps the prophecy might be referring to someone... some THING different. Like... science."

"You may be right, but I don't think that's the full picture. The elements must be 'sought, understood and embraced', not just commanded. I think that it's both. Someone who not just commands their power, but understands the Elements of Harmony and embraces their ideals."

"Yes... It's almost like, the prophecy is saying, the world has to... I don't know... be united in both Friendship and Science? It's like I've always told Harry, just because you can do it alone doesn't mean you have to. There's a whole world out there of people with different experiences and different lives, you can't just assume you're the only person who really knows how things are."

Twilight thought about this for a bit. "That does seem right. But then, where do we go from here? I mean, not 'we' like the world, but 'we' like you and me."

"And what am I, chopped horse meat?" Discord interjected incredulously.

Twilight sighed, "You can come along too if you want..." she trailed off and muttered a bit, "Not that you need my permission..."

Discord chuckled, "No, no. I'm perfectly fine where I'm at, observing things from a distance, pulling little strings and loose threads wherever I find them." Discord suddenly gasped and held a claw up to his mouth. "But dear me, I realized how terribly rude I've been!"

"What do you mean?"

"You asked a question earlier that I never got around to answering. You asked, why does it feel different? It's simple, really: she's alive, now."

"What?!" Hermione exclaimed.

"Alive and well! I'd show you myself, but we have an unexpected visitor who I think will illustrate the point far more vividly. Mr. Malfoy, would you like to introduce yourself?"

"Mr. Malfoy?!" Hermione shouted.

"I... are you there? Is someone there?" Lucius Malfoy's voice floated eerily from a place beyond places.

"Lucius Malfoy, what is he doing here?" Hermione demanded.

Discord bobbed up and down impatiently, "Normally I would let you all take a chapter or two to figure out together how all of this came to be, but we're running quite short on time. So many places to go, so many people to be, you know how it is."

Discord clapped his paw and claw together, and the form of Lucius Malfoy melted into existence out of the nothingness.

Malfoy looked around, thoroughly disoriented until he saw the two unicorns and odd dragon-like creature standing in front of him.

"What are you doing here, Mr. Malfoy?" Hermione once again demanded.

"Do... Do I know you?" Lucius asked, urgently.

"Yes, it's me, Hermione Granger, how could you forg- Oh." She realized that she was currently presenting as a unicorn rather than her human self. She concentrated hard, willing her form to change into what she seemed to remember she looked like, a process she found much easier now that she was apparently alive.

Malfoy nodded, uncharacteristically frightened and discomposed, "Yes, Miss Granger. Yes... Listen, we don't have much time. Draco and Harry, they're in danger. I... I can still feel the world around me, I don't think I'm quite dead yet-"

"Dead?!" Hermione exclaimed.

"Yes, murdered by a servant of Lord Voldemort. He is returned," Lucius said, simply. "My life in that world is draining quickly... Just... Look."

Lucius closed his eyes and concentrated, and around them, a scene began to unfold; a strange, menacing figure that was too tall to be human, standing over Harry and Draco and a collection of witches, one of whom was touching Harry's hand-

"My friends!" Twilight shouted with an exhilaration that soon gave way to fright as she saw the predicament they were in.

The voices were too muffled to be heard, but it was clear that Lucius Malfoy was telling the truth; they were all in grave danger.

While Twilight was focused on her friends and the knives at their throats, Hermione was transfixed by something else entirely: her own form upon the altar, her own chest rising slowly up and down, her own blood pumping through her own heart of its own volition.

The scene around them was becoming more and more solid, more real.

"He... Harry did it. He really did it. I'm... I'm alive," Hermione whispered, tears beginning to form at the corners of her eyes. "My friend. My friend saved me...

The forest began to encroach in around them, with black hooded figures circling menacingly above.

"He saved me... because he is my friend... And now..."

Beneath the moonlight glints a tiny fragment of silver, a fraction of a line...

Hermione drew herself up to her full height, "Now, I have to save him. Because he is my friend... and..."

(Black robes, falling)

Twilight gasped as she saw the knives that were pressed against the throats of her friends move with sudden, savage ferocity.

...blood spills out in liters

"Friendship... is... MAGIC!"

...and someone screams a word.

"EXPECTO PATRONUM!"